字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
宝贝 真高兴看到你
Hey, babe. So happy to see you!
我收到你的花了 你真贴心
Hi! I got your flowers. That was so sweet of you.
应该的 你今天要完成全球卫生报告
Of course. Well, I know you're finishing your Global Health paper today
而且你工作的很辛苦
and you've been working really hard on it.
我快做好了 所以也许…
Well, I'm almost done, so, maybe
你可以过来看影片聊聊天 然后…
you want to come over and Netflix and chill and...
什么？
What?
你是说你想来一炮？
You mean you want to fuck?
我才没这样说
I did not say that!
- 我的天啊  - 我懂的
- Oh, my God!  - I know.
不 我说的委婉多了
No! I was being more subtle than that!
我知道 抱歉
I know. I'm sorry.
好 我超想去的
Yes, I am so down for that.
都过了他妈的三天了
It's been like three fucking days.
我的蛋蛋都闷成蓝色了
My balls are so blue right now,
深蓝色 快变铁蛋了
like dark blue, Uh-oh. Like almost black.
真心不骗啦 你自己看
No, I'm fucking serious. Here, check it out.
我相信你…
I believe you. I believe you.
好吧
Okay.
我晚点再看你的铁蛋
I'll see your almost-black balls later.
你说了算
Cool, Steph.
六点之后随时欢迎 好吗？
Come over any time after 6:00. Okay, hun?
好 我们会超激烈地“看片聊天”
Okay. Dude, we are going to Netflix and chill this shit so hard.
“浴血黑帮”“打不倒的金咪”
Peaky Blinders. Kimmy Schmidt!
胡子月过了
Movember's over.
你该刮掉色魔胡了
Time to shave the pornstache.
抱歉 “制造杀人犯”
Sorry. Making a Murderer!
“毒枭”
Narcos!
“怪奇物语”
Stranger Things!
铁蛋来了
Black balls!
[苹果蜂街坊烧烤酒吧]
[奈德55岁生日快乐！]
总之 奈德追随他的梦想
Anyways, Ned followed his dreams
把一部老旧印刷机变成业界巨头
and turned a run-down old printing press into the industry powerhouse
也就是现在的弗莱明公司
known today as the Fleming Company.
老板最棒了
Best boss in the world!
弗莱明公司
The Fleming Company!
我们做过…
We're talking
世楷家具的型录
brochures for Steelcase furniture,
大城里半数的工作手册
half the specialty jobs in Grand Rapids
[是男孩！]
还有难忘的达美乐披萨传单
and who could forget the Domino's Pizza circular?
[网购披萨半价]
[中西部媒体协会年度人物]
但在这一切之前
But before all that...
他遇见了密西根金钢狼 芭芭拉威许
Ned met a young Michigan Wolverine, Barbara Welsh.
这个阿伯怎么把到我的？
How did this older guy get me?
他们首次约会就去看他最爱的乐团
Ned took her on their first date to see his favorite band...
- 吻乐团  - 吻乐团
- Kiss!  - Kiss!
[吻乐团]
也是我最爱的团
My favorite band, too!
摇滚乐
Rock and roll!
过了几年
A few years later,
送子鸟带来我姐姐 史黛芬
the stork brought my sister, Stephanie.
她好可爱
She's so cute.
他们一点都不亲
They weren't close at all.
- 送她上学超累的  - 是啊
- Oh, dropping her off at school.  - Yeah.
接着我报到了 史考特小子
Then came me, Scotty F.
我们还生了另一个小孩？
Did we have another child?
- 我都忘了有生老二  - 原来还有老二
- I forgot about that second baby.  - Oh, we had another child.
总之 老大
Anyways, Big Cheese.
不好意思 我答应自己不哭的
I'm sorry, guys. I promised myself I wasn't gonna do this.
但我爱你 爸 生日快乐
But I love you, Dad. Happy Birthday.
做得好 史考特
Way to go, Scotty!
我也爱你 小子
I love you, too, buddy.
谢谢你
Thank you. Wow!
做得太棒了
That was fantastic.
我们还有最后的惊喜
We've got one last surprise for you.
没错 现在要连线斯坦福大学宿舍
That's right. Ladies and gentlemen, live from her dorm room at Stanford...
给我姐姐 史黛芬
it's my sister, Stephanie!
- 大家好  - 乖女儿
- Hi, everyone!  - Hey, honey!
史黛芬 是我 凯文
Hey, Steph! Hey, it's Kevin!
- 嗨 凯文  - 凯文
- Hi, Kevin!  - Kevin.
- 我们可以看吗？ - 抱歉
- Can we see?  - Sorry.
- 妈妈  - 女儿
- Hi, Momma.  - Hi!
爸
Hi, Dad.
我们的寿星
The birthday boy.
宝贝女儿
Hey, honey.
看来你们玩得很开心
You guys look like you're having so much fun.
真希望我也能到场
And I wish I could be there with you.
她好贴心哦
She's so sweet.
- 是啊  - 走开
- Yeah.  - Get out.
我只想说 爸 我爱你
Yeah, I just wanted to say, Dad, that I love you.
我也爱你 乖女儿
I love you, too, honey.
- 我更爱你  - 少来了
- I love you more.  - No, you don't.
我对你爱爱爱不完
Love you to the moon and back.
这回合先让你赢 好吗？
I'll let you win this round. Okay, Pops?
虽然你现在已经是…
Even though you're now like...
老阿伯
...ancient.
你还是…
You are still...
你怎么会在这里？
What are you doing here?
你叫我来的啊
You asked me to come over.
你来早了 我说六点以后的
You're early. I said after 6:00.
- 好吧  - 等一下 我在打电话
- All right.  - Give me a sec, I'm on the phone.
- 收到  - 抱歉 是我朋友
- Got it.  - Sorry. It's just my friend. Anyway.
♪ 祝你生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
老天爷
Oh, my goodness.
莱德 你在做什…
Oh, Laird, what are you...
你先讲电话
Go finish your call.
我在准备“看片聊天” 宝贝
I'm just getting ready to Netflix and chill, baby.
- 现在不行啦  - 天啊
- No, not now, Laird.  - Oh, my goodness.
“打不倒的金咪”
Kimmy Schmidt!
- 裤子穿好啦  -“马可·波罗”
- Pull up your pants.  - Marco Polo.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
要怎么关掉？
How do you make it stop?
妈 你刚刚截图了
Whoa, whoa, Mom, you just took a screenshot.
♪ 快乐 生日快乐… ♪
♪ Happy, happy birthday Happy, happy birthday ♪
凯文 快帮她关掉
Kevin, help her out. Kevin.
♪ 祝你生日快乐… ♪
♪ Happy birthday, happy birthday ♪
《为什么是他》
♪ Mi oh my, it's a wonderful life ♪
[弗莱明公司]
[成立于1991年]
♪ It's a wonderful life with you by my side ♪
♪ Mi oh my, it's a wonderful life ♪
他来了 生日快乐 老大
Hey, there he is. Happy birthday, Big Cheese.
谢了 吉姆
Thanks, Jim.
杰瑞
Jerry. Hey, Ned.
- 昨晚的晚餐真好玩  - 好说
- Fun dinner last night.  - Hey, Jerry.
谢了 小卢
Thanks. Lou.
老大 我们得谈谈
Hey, Cheese, can I have a minute?
好 早安 乔伊丝
Sure. Good morning, Joyce.
派对很棒
Great party.
挡掉所有电话
Hold all his calls.
你在开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
大超市要跟我们切了？
Big Lots is bailing out on us?
他们从〇六年就是我们的客户
We've had that account since '06.
他们要把印刷业务移到中国
They're moving all their print work to China.
天啊
Oh, God.
“E请帖”和“无邮无虑”等网站
Cheese, we're already getting pummeled by Evite, Stamp-Free
已经把我们害惨了
and the rest of those dot-coms.
再这样下去 我们三月就破产了
And at this rate, we'll be Chapter 11 by March.
迪克体育用品呢？
What about Dick's Sporting Goods?
我还在跟我的联络人谈
Well, I mean, I'm still trading calls with my guy.
奈德 可以老实跟你说吗？
But, Ned, can I be honest with you?
我不能再瞒着派蒂了
I can't keep this from Patty much longer.
公司不是一直有我撑着吗？
Lou, haven't I kept us going?
对 这个你最会了
Yeah. I mean, it's what you do.
我只需要多一点时间罢了
I just need a little more time. That's all.
你是大师
You are the maestro.
也许你会创造圣诞奇迹
Maybe you'll pull off a Christmas miracle.
- 是啊  - 是啊
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
对了 你昨晚表现得真镇定
By the way, good job keeping that game face last night.
谢了
Oh. Thanks.
很好玩的聚会
That was some shindig, man.
是很好玩
Yeah, it was fun.
直到那小子的3D屁股占满荧幕
Well, till the kid had his farter all over the screen in 3-D.
我心想“哇”
I was like, "Whoa!
“太夸张了”
"That's a lot, man."
而且…
And get this...
史黛芬要我们飞过去
Stephanie now wants us to fly out...
趁放假认识那个股沟后的男人
to meet the man behind the crack over the holidays.
想到公司的状况 我根本没心情去
With everything that's going on here, that's the last thing I want to do.
等等 这是她第一个认真的对象？
Well, hold on now. This is the first serious boyfriend?
显然是如此
Yeah. Apparently.
真的很奇怪
I mean, it's so strange.
我跟史黛芬一直都很亲
I mean, Stephanie and I have always been so close.
她却从来没提过这家伙
And yet she has never even mentioned this guy.
都嘛是这样 老大
That's the way it goes, Cheese.
我也以为我很了解小小卢
I thought I knew everything about Lou Junior,
他去俄亥俄念大学后
when he was down at Ohio State.
突然带了同校的女生回家
Out of nowhere, he comes dragging home this Buckeye
还说已经交往一年多了
that he's been dating for over a year.
- 不会吧  - 真的
- No.  - Yeah.
她是个好女孩 不过控制欲好强
Nice girl, but still. She's so controlling.
抱歉 我不是那个意思
I'm sorry. I don't mean it like that
我跟她不够熟 但我就是讨厌她
because I don't know her that well. But I don't like her.
- 真的  - 小卢
- I don't.  - Lou.
这种事就是会发生
It's just what happens, you know?
小卢 讲重点好吗？
Lou, what is the point of all this?
飞过去认识他吧
Go out there and meet him.
我知道公司现在有些状况
I know we going through a lot right now
但小小卢已经在说五月要结婚
but hell, Lou Junior is talking about getting married in May.
结婚
Married.
一旦他们离家以后
Once they're not under your roof,
你再也搞不懂他们了
there's no telling what they're into.
对了 他想请你在婚礼上致词
Oh, uh, that reminds me. He does want you to speak at the wedding
美言几句
and say some kind words. Oh.
我答应他会问你看看
I told him that I would talk to you about it.
而且他们想在你家后院结婚
And they'd like to get married at your house in the backyard.
- 这…  - 反正啊
- Well...  - But anyway...
我想你可能该去认识一下这小子
I'm just saying you might want to get out there and meet this kid.
因为你也看到了
Because, I mean, you saw it.
他是个大鸣大放的人
You saw it, he's a free spirit.
你是说…
You mean...
你也听到他走进房间
You heard him come into the room.
提枪快跑的样子
He came in there guns blazing.
他弹药满满 已经准备要…
He had that revved up energy where he was like...
啪…啪…啪…啪…
bow-bow-bow-bow.
他只想要冲冲冲
He just wants to go and go and go...
照三餐喊“史黛芬 我来了”
and just morning, noon and night, and "Stephanie, here I am.
“史黛芬 我来了 我又要来了”
"Stephanie, here I come. I'm coming again."
我记得那年纪是怎么回事
I remember being that age, don't you?
总是精虫冲脑
Just always ready.
[12月22日 圣荷西国际机场]
♪ Come on, it's lovely weather ♪
♪ For a sleigh ride together with you ♪
谢谢你们来看我
Thanks for coming.
天啊 这里太美了
Oh, gosh, it is so gorgeous here.
你们都来了 让我好兴奋
I'm very excited that you guys are all out here.
我们也很兴奋
We're very excited.
有几件关于莱德的事要告诉你们
There's a few things that I wanna tell you about Laird
我不想在电话里讲 因为…
that I didn't feel like getting into over the phone because...
女儿…
Watch, honey...
[38号出口]
你错过出口了
You missed our exit.
其实我是故意的
Actually, I missed it on purpose.
我跟莱德认为…
Laird and I thought,
我们都借住他家会比较好
it'd be better if we all stayed at his house.
他家？
His house?
什么时候的事？你事先知道吗？
When did this come up? Did you know about this?
你确定他爸妈有足够的空间？
Are you sure his parents have enough room?
他没有跟爸妈住在一起
I mean, he doesn't live with his parents.
我们在小套房会住得很不舒服
Honey, we're not gonna be comfortable at some crash pad.
他自己住 也不是小套房
He lives by himself. It's not a crash pad,
而且比喜来登高档多了
but it's much nicer than the Sheraton.
比贵宾楼层还高档？
Nicer than the club floor?
我吹捧了经理 用客房价订到套房
I smooth-talked the manager. We got a suite at the regular rate.
你最上道了 老大
What? That's what I'm talking about, Big Cheese.
- 真有你的  - 我们必须调头
- That is impressive.  - We have to turn back.
- 免费欧陆早餐  - 没错
- Free continental breakfast.  - Yes.
枕头香氛 开床服务 应有尽有
Mint on the pillow, turndown service, all things available at the Sheraton.
你的爱人会有那些吗？
I mean, is your lover going to have that?
你的“爱人”？
Your lover? Your lover?
我们都知道你看过他的鸟了
We already all know that you've seen his penis.
- 什么？ - 史考特
- What?  - Scott!
干嘛？
What?
[大学街 帕罗奥图]
♪ Sleigh bells ring Are you listening ♪
他家真可爱
Well, this is cute.
其实这是警卫室
Actually, this is the gatehouse.
警卫室？
Gatehouse?
♪ A beautiful sight We're happy tonight ♪
搞什么？
What the heck?
那是脸部辨识扫描机吗？
Is that a facial recognition scanner?
好酷哦
That's so cool.
♪ Gone away is the bluebird Here to stay is the new bird ♪
树篱在动耶
The hedge is moving.
♪ He sings a love song As we go along ♪
♪ Walking in a winter wonderland ♪
女儿 你到底在跟谁交往？
Honey, who exactly are you dating?
莱德创办了叫”游击帮”的公司
Laird started this company called Guerrilla Gang.
你有玩“猿人刺客”吧？
You play Ape Assassins, right?
那当然 它是我八年级时的最爱
Are you kidding me? Yeah, that was my jam in the eighth grade.
很好 那是他做的
Great, that's him.
他是做电玩的？
So, he makes video games?
- 是应用程式  - 我们到了
- Apps, Dad.  - This is it!
这里是他家？
This is his house? Mmm-hmm.
你确定这里不是苹果专卖店？
Are you sure this isn't an Apple Store or something?
我的天 你们好吗？
Oh, my God. What is up, you gang?
你看他们
I know!
弗莱明一家终于到了
The Flemings are here. You have arrived!
你好啊
Hi, buddy. Hi.
你好 小甜心
Hello, sweetheart.
- 什么都别碰  - 交通顺畅吗？
- Don't touch anything.  - How was traffic?
- 还好 他们来了  - 你好
- It was okay.  - Hi, they're here! Hello.
你好 奈德·弗莱明
Hello to you, Ned Fleming.
- 芭芭拉  - 是
- Barbara.  - Yes.
你太完美了
You are perfect.
谢谢你 我的天
Well, thank you. Oh, my God.
这位一定是人气王史考特
And this must be the main man. Scotty, huh?
- 没错  - 很好
- Yup. All right.  - Hey.
- 你是谁？ - 古斯塔
- Who are you?  - Gustav.
是的 我是古斯塔
I am Gustav. Yes.
我都不知道该怎么形容你
I never know how to describe you.
物业经理就行了 史黛芬
Um, well, estate manager is cool, Stephy, yes.
很合适
That works.
我在亚洲经营过四季饭店集团
I used to run the Four Seasons group in Asia
但到了一个阶段
but after some point, you know,
企业生活就变得有点无聊
the corporate life becomes a bit of a snooze-fest.
一下蒂芬妮 一下卡地亚
You know, "Tiffany's this, Cartier that."
简直点点点 真是够了
But, you know. Just dot, dot, dot. Enough already.
你一定懂我的意思 奈德
You know what I'm talking about, Ned.
当然
Oh, yeah. Sure.
超无聊
Boring.
- 莱德呢？ - 他在楼上
- Where's Laird?  - Laird is upstairs.
他的电话会议快结束了
He is just finishing a teleconference.
- 他马上就出来  - 那我们上去吧…
- He'll be right out.  - Oh, okay. Why don't we go up then?
- 莱德 我是奈德  - 不…
- Laird, I'm Ned.  - No, no, no.
- 蓝迪是实习生  - 他不是莱德
- No, this is Randy.  - That's not Laird.
刚从麻省理工学院毕业的优等生
Just graduated summa cum laude at MIT.
蓝迪 快帮他们提行李
So Randy, shake a leg. Get their luggages.
是
Yes, sir.
屌他妈的弗莱明一家大驾光临
The motherfucking Flemings are in the house!
水啦
Yes!
实在他妈的屌呀
This is fucking awesome!
快上来 我超想见你们的
Get up here. I'm so psyched to meet you.
全家福耶 屌爆了
Family, baby. Fuck yeah!
老天爷
Oh, my God.
史考特
Scotty.
小老弟 欢迎你
Yes, my brotha! Welcome.
- 芭芭拉  - 你好
- Hey, Barb.  - Hi.
欢迎
Welcome.
奈德 好耶 太棒了
Hey, Ned. All right. Oh, yes.
太棒了…
Yes. Yes.
- 太棒了  - 真高兴见到你
- Yes.  - So glad you're here.
- 太棒了  - 嗨
- Yes. Hey.  - Hi.
- 宝贝  - 嗨
- Hey, baby.  - Hi.
我超他妈想你的
I fucking missed you.
你身上为什么没穿衣服？
Why aren't you wearing a shirt on your body? Oh.
别担心这个 我有个小惊喜
Don't worry about that. I have a little surprise.
我们待个半小时就回饭店
Let's stay half an hour and then we go back to the hotel.
- 好计划 谢谢你  - 可是这里好狂
- That's a good plan. Thank you.  - Dad, come on. This place is so sick.
- 是很狂  - 二十五分钟就好
- Yeah, it's sick.  - 25 minutes.
好
That's it.
放过那女孩
Hey! Just leave her alone.
奈德…
Hey, oh, Ned. Ned.
奈德 你看那个
Ned, would you look at that.
姐 那是你的脸耶
That's your face, Sis. Oh.
还真像
Very good likeness.
谢谢
Oh, thanks. Yeah.
这刺青是在我们相识一周后刺的
The Stephy tattoo. I got it, like, a week after we met, right?
- 一周啊  - 就在我心口上
- One week.  - You know, right on my heart.
好了 你们想参观一下吗？
Great. Okay, do you guys want to go see the house?
我们可能该…
Uh... We probably should...
- 我们只是来打招呼  - 对 该走了
- We came to stop and say hey.  - Yeah. We should go.
不行
Actually, no.
不行 在参观前
No. Before we go, um...
我要给大家一个小惊喜
I have a little surprise for everybody.
靠 我他妈的超紧张
Shit. I'm fucking nervous.
你想先问问我吗？先谈过你再…
Do you want to consult me about it? You want to talk to me before you...
不管了 我要直接冲了
You know what? No, I'm just jumpin' in. All right?
乔落去就对了 这一定会屌到翻
I'm just going to do this. Laird, it's going to be fucking great.
登登
Ta-da!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
[圣诞快乐！]
我今天早上才刺的
I just got it done this morning
一定还很红吧？
Yeah. I bet it's red, huh?
我需要一点评语
I need a little feedback.
- 那是我们的圣诞卡吗？ - 对
- Is that our Christmas card?  - Yes.
我就是用那张卡 你们怎么知道？
Yeah! That's exactly what I used. How'd you know?
他连面条都刺上去了
Look, he even got Noodle in there.
痛惨了
Hurt like balls.
天啊 他还刺了“圣诞快乐”
Gosh, it says "Happy Holidays" and everything.
什么？
What?
- 他妈的少乱说  - 好
- Get the fuck out of here.  - Okay.
他刺了“圣诞快乐”？
It says "Happy Holidays?"
去你妈的
Barb, fuck you.
夭寿哦
God damn.
没想到师傅把卡片上的字也刺上去
I gave the guy the Christmas card. I didn't know he put "Happy Holidays" on there.
- 哇  - 妈的
- Wow.  - Fuck.
这句话会甲我揽牢牢了
Guess it's stuck on there, huh?
- 糟糕  - 妈的
- Oops.  - Fuck.
因为你们要过来
Well, you know, you guys were coming over...
我太兴奋了 非做点什么不可
I was so excited, I just had to do something, you know?
那真的很特别
Well, that is something, all right.
有时候只能说句“去他妈的”就算了
You know what? Sometimes, you just got to say, "Fuck it."
去他妈的
Fuck it!
- 你应该…  - 莱德
- You should...  - Laird,
他才十五岁
this is a 15-year-old child.
所以我们不太…
So, we don't really...
靠
Oh, shit.
- 你不说“他妈的”？ - 妈 我…
- You don't say fuck?  - No, Mom, I...
我当然会讲脏话
Heck yeah, I cuss.
你才不会
No, you don't.
- 你会吗？ - 会啊
- You do?  - Yeah.
他会讲脏话
Oh, he cusses.
- 你不会啦  - 你最喜欢谯哪一句？
- No, you don't.  - Yeah, bro, what's your favorite cuss word?
天啊
Oh, boy.
- 别怂恿他啦  - 你最爱哪一句？
- Don't egg him on like that.No, you don't.  - What's your favorite?
奶子
Titties.
奶子？奶子啊
Titties? Titties.
别说了
Stop it. Stop that.
奶子？真经典
Titties? Classic.
好了 我们该走了
Okay. We should be going.
- 不错哦 还有什么？ - 臭菊花
- Nice one. What else you got?  - Asshole.
- 臭菊花  - 好了 够了
- Asshole.  - All right. That's enough.
那也是很棒的身体部位
Okay. Another good body part.
- 还有什么？ - 抽插 双插
- What else?  - Dicking. Double dicking.
- 双插  - 行了
- Double dicking.  - Okay.
等等 双插？
Wait. Hold on. Double dicking?
- 你满意了吗？ - 这个我没听过
- Are you happy?  - That's a new one on me, bro.
那是什么玩意儿？
What the fuck is that?
那是啥？是鸟对鸟的意思吗？
What the hell is that? Is that like dick to dick?
好了 晚安 我们要去饭店了
Okay! Good night! We're going to the hotel.
这小子坏透了 我他妈爱死他了
This kid is nasty and I fucking like it.
- 水啦  - 好耶
- Yeah.  - Yes!
我们开始参观吧
All right, let's do the tour.
我带你们到处看看 好吗？
I'll show you around! All right?
垃圾行李随便丢
Just throw your shit anywhere.
- 双插男 来吧  - 东西放着就好
- You little double-dicker, come on.  - Throw your stuff anywhere.
我是铁粉 我有加入线上猿人军
By the way, I'm a huge fan. I'm part of the online Ape Army.
赞哦
Awesome.
这就是我在车上想告诉你们的事
You know, this is what I was trying to tell you guys in the car.
可以放这里吗？
This is okay here?
你想把外套脱掉吗？
Do you want to take your coat off?
不用了 我很好
Uh, no. Nope. I'm fine.
来吧 各位
Come on, guys.
这里是厨房 我们放食物的地方
All right, so this here's the kitch. This is where we keep the food.
餐厅
The dining room.
那是两个人在嘿咻的雕像
That's a sculpture of a couple people fucking.
[胖松鼠]
一只胖松鼠的画
Painting of a fat squirrel.
[三匹鹿]
这一幅叫“三匹鹿” 很好懂吧
And this one's called "Triple Team," self-explanatory.
这里是我们的巢穴
All right. This is the den.
他们只是在测试游戏
These dudes are just testing out video games.
奈德 史黛芬说你很爱打保龄球
Ned, Stephy says that you're pretty serious about your bowling,
所以我装了两个球道
so I had a couple lanes installed.
天啊
Oh, my God.
这是全新的？
None of this was here?
没错
No.
你说你在修理地基的裂缝
You said you were fixing a crack in the foundation.
那是我们吗？
Is that us?
对 照片是从你们社团的脸书抓的
Yeah, I got the images off your league's Facebook page.
太狂了
That's so insane.
爸 有你的招牌动作“胯下斩”耶
Dad, look, he even got in your signature "crotch chop."
对耶
Oh, yeah.
哇
Wow.
这里是我们为苹果跟安卓平台
All right, this here is where we develop a few apps
开发应用程式的地方
for the Apple and Android platforms.
你们快跟弗莱明一家问好
Hey, gang, say hi to the Flemings.
- 你们好  - 你们好吗？
- Hey, guys.  - Hey, what's up?
等等 你的员工住在这里？
Wait, I don't understand. Do your employees live here?
有些人可能是 我也搞不清楚
Uh, maybe some of them do. I don't really know.
古斯塔其实是很神的建筑师
Gustav is actually an amazing architect.
这里是我们一起设计的
We designed this place together.
你什么时候去了马丘比丘？
When did you go to Machu Picchu?
这是什么时候放的？
Hun, when did you put these up?
那头麋鹿是怎么回事？
What the heck is that moose?
那是菲利普曼费迪的作品
That's a Phillip Manfredi.
好眼光 芭芭拉
Great pick-up, Barb.
听说你是很厉害的艺术和摄影教授
Stephy told me that you're this amazing art and photography professor.
- 有够犀利  - 嗯嗯
- That's awesome.  - Mmm-hmm.
我只是在社区大学教两堂课
I teach a couple of classes at a local community college.
别谦虚 妈 你是很棒的摄影师
Don't be so modest, Mom. You're an amazing photographer.
它看起来就像真的死麋鹿
Oh, that looks like a real dead moose.
被你说中了 奈德
Well, that's exactly what it is, Ned.
泡在自己尿里的死麋鹿
A dead moose suspended in its own urine.
象征了文化是如何禁锢我们的心灵
It's meant to symbolize the way that our culture has imprisoned our minds.
我得说 好艺术让我欲火焚身
I got to tell you, Ned, great art really gets me aroused.
简直就像强力春药
It's actually a very strong aphrodisiac.
莱德
Laird.
倒不是说那位美魔女还不够诱人
Not that you need any help getting turned on by that gorgeous woman.
宝贝
Honey.
干嘛？你妈妈很美啊
What? Your mom is beautiful.
- 她是啊  - 她值得被称赞
- She is.  - She deserves some props for that.
有人敢夸我就敢听
Well, I'll take a compliment wherever I can get one.
那我继续说 你的身材很火辣
Well, here's another one. You got a bangin' bod, too.
好的
All right.
大家好啊
Hey, what's going on, everyone?
这位是理查·布莱斯
Richard Blais, everybody.
他是分子厨艺大师
This is the maestro of molecular gastronomy.
老天 是“顶级主厨”里那个帅哥
Oh, my God. That's that cute one from Top Chef.
他是老爱说“砰”的那个
Oh, he's the one who goes, "Bam!"
那是艾莫利 那家伙是个烂咖
No, that's Emeril. He's a fucking dick, that guy.
阿布 什么事？
Dickie Blais what's up?
莱德觉得今晚为你们做个快闪餐厅
Yeah, so Laird thought it would be a fun idea to do a pop-up restaurant
会很好玩
just in your honor tonight.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Did he?  - Yeah.
我做了醒嘴的小点
And I have here a little amuse-bouche.
如果有人想吃晚餐前的小点心
So if anyone's looking for a little pre-dinner snack,
可以过来这里
you can head on up here.
太好了 因为我饿扁了
Count me in, 'cause I'm famished.
好耶
All right.
你的惊喜还真多
There are so many surprises.
我知道
I know.
饿肚子的人来对地方了
You're hungry, you've come to the right place.
我为你们准备了海陆飨宴
I've got surf and turf for you.
牛排和龙虾
Steak and lobster.
太好了
Yum, yum.
我的版本有食用土和浮游生物泡沫
My version of surf and turf, edible soil and plankton foam.
请用
Dig in. Oh.
我等不及要吃晚餐了
Wow, can't wait for dinner.
免了
No.
我觉得进行得很顺利耶
Hey, so I think it's going great, right?
我看他们已经接受我了
I think they've already accepted me.
我接收到的讯号不太一样
I'm getting a little bit of a different vibe.
真假？怎么说？
Oh, really? Like what?
别太刻意
Don't try so hard.
我哪有 你是什么意思？
I'm not, what do you mean?
你为我爸装了保龄球道
You put in a bowling alley for my dad
还把我全家人刺在你背上
and you got a tattoo of my entire family on your back.
刺青太过火了吗？
Was the tattoo too much?
- 对  - 妈的
- Yes.  - Fuck.
靠 我就知道
Shit, I knew it.
古斯塔也说过一样的话
Yeah, Gustav said the same thing.
好 别担心
Okay, don't worry...
我暂时不会再刺有他们的刺青了
I won't get any more tattoos of them while they're here.
- 谢谢你  - 没问题
- Thank you.  - Okay.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
好吧
Okay.
还有 别再对他们烙脏话
Oh, one more thing, stop calling them motherfuckers
或说我妈有多辣了
and talking about how hot my mom is.
她出乎意料的性感 我惊呆了
Well, she's sneaky sexy, took me by surprise.
她是个辣妈 正港的辣妈
Dude, she is a MILF, like a genuine MILF.
如果她不是你妈 就是个“搞妈”
And if it wasn't your MILF, she'd be a MIWF...
我想搞的妈
a mother I would fuck.
- 但是我不会  - 好
- But I won't.  - Okay.
- 废话  - 谢谢你
- Of course.  - Thank you.
- 好啦 这里很美  - 是啊
- All right, it's pretty.  - Yeah.
我…
You know...
是很夸张
It's a lot.
- 对 那麋鹿…  - 对
- Yes! I mean, the moose...  - Yes.
那些粗话 拜托哦
And the language. Come on!
真正的麋鹿耶
Mmm-hmm. A real moose!
- 他还调戏你妈  - 很糟糕
- And he's coming onto your mother.  - That's not okay.
还有刺青？
And the tattoo?
那刺青…他多大…？
The tattoo! And how...
- 三十二岁  - 我的天 你才…
- 32  - Oh, my. And you're...
- 二十二岁  - 没错
- 22.  - Yes!
你不喜欢保龄球道上的壁画？
You didn't like the mural of you and Scotty down in the new bowling alley?
保龄球道跟壁画…那是标准球道
The bowling alley with the mural is... And the bowling alley is regulation.
是蛮不错的
That's quite nice
很少有人有那么好的东西
and that's very rare to have something that nice.
他用的抛光蜡也很好 但是…
And the polish that he used was quite... It was good. But...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我早该告诉你的
I should have told you.
对你坦白一切
About everything, of course.
我不知道该怎么在电话里介绍他
Honestly, I didn't know how to explain him over the phone.
我一直想像…
I just kept imagining...
妈会上网搜寻莱德
Mom Googling Laird Mayhew
你们会在认识他之前就先下断论
and you guys jumping to conclusions before you even got a chance to know him.
现在我们认识他了
Well, now we know him.
还没有 你们才到十五分钟
No, you don't. You've been here for 15 minutes.
是啊
Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是你们第一次没在家过圣诞节
I wouldn't have asked you to come out here and miss Christmas in Michigan
我会特地邀你们来都是因为…
for the first time ever, if he wasn't...
他对我真的很重要
...really important to me.
好吧
Okay.
你会给他一个机会？
You'll give him a chance?
- 好  - 谢谢你…
- Okay.  - Okay, thank you. Thank you.
过来
Come here.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
如果我上网搜寻他 会看到什么？
So if I did Google him, what would I find?
别这么做
Don't do it.
不要搜寻他
Don't search for him.
我还是看不懂
Well, I still don't see it.
这个是男的 他在“挺进”
Darling, this is the male, and he's thrusting.
我的天
Oh, God.
各位 晚餐上桌了
All right, everybody, dinner is served!
史考特 找个树桩坐
Scotty! Come on, grab a stump.
爸 你坐那里吧 妈
Dad, you wanna go there? Mom.
你确定你不要脱掉外套？
You sure you don't want to take off your coat?
不用 我很好
No. I'm good.
这里走家庭风 大家就开动吧
We do it family style here, so everyone just dig in.
随意就好
It's super cas.
今天晚上有三道菜
Okay, so we have three dishes for this evening.
舒煨象拔蚌
We have sous-vide geoduck.
- 豪饱海胆卷饼  - 好耶
- We have Mission-style sea urchin burritos...  - Yum.
搭配食用纸
...with edible paper.
因为你是印刷商
Because you're a printer.
- 最后则是…  - 真贴心
- And last but not least...  - Sweet.
烟燻加州熊
...we have smoked California bear.
- 请慢用  - 靠
- Enjoy.  - Oh, shit!
谢了 阿布
Thanks, Blais.
- 熊？ - 嗯嗯
- Bear?  - Mmm.
史考特 看过神鬼猎人吗？
Yo, Scotty, you see The Revenant?
我想但爸妈不肯让我看限制级电影
No, I wanted to, but my parents don't really let me watch R-rated movies.
- 你是不该看  - 他才十五岁
- You're darn right we don't.  - He's only 15.
- 要报纸吗？ - 当然好 谢谢
- You want some paper?  - Yes, certainly. Thank you.
不知道这是哪一版
I don't know what section that is.
那只熊超机歪 现在换我们搞死它
Because that bear fucked that dude up! Now we're gonna fuck this bear up.
不是说要注意用词？
Hey, what about that language?
靠 抱歉
Oh, shit. Sorry.
我想我拿到艺术版了
Ah, I think I've got the arts section here.
你最好吃慢一点
You better slow down, Barb.
否则还没到笑话版就饱了
You're gonna be full before you get to the funnies.
奈德
Ned.
你们俩怎么认识的？
So, um, how did you two meet?
- 我来说？ - 好啊
- Uh, you want me to go?  - Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
莱德和刘博士办了一场校园讲座
Laird sponsored a talk on campus with Doctor Joanne Liu,
她是无国界医生组织的主席
the head of Doctors Without Borders.
喔
Oh!
梅琳达盖兹
Melinda Gates got me totally pumped
我就回不去了
Now I'm obsessed.
哇
Wow.
- 那是比尔盖兹的老婆  - 对
- That's Bill Gates' wife.  - Yeah.
- 她很棒  - 是啊
- She's great.  - Yeah.
了不起
That's terrific.
史黛芬也对这领域有兴趣
That's Steph's field of interest, too, so that's great.
我知道 你该看看她在讲座的表现
Yeah, I know. Ned, you should've seen her at the talk.
她问的问题充满智慧 我都傻了
She asked the most intelligent question. I was blown away.
我说了什么？
Really? What did I say?
你说…
You were like...
“原民族群的妇女健康跟人口密度”
"Hey, what's the connection between "women's health and population density
“有什么关系？”
"in indigenous communities?"
我心想“她是谁啊？”
I was like, "Bam! Who's that?"
你还记得真是窝心
That's so sweet of you to remember that.
我当然记得
Of course I remember. Mmm...
- 第一次见到你…  - 她就是这样
- The first time I saw you.  - That's our girl.
她总是最聪明的那个
She's always been the smartest person in the room.
- 没错  - 是啊
- So true.  - Yeah.
- 也是最性感的 天啊  - 这…
- And the sexiest. My God.  - Well.
我无法不看着她
I couldn't keep my eyes off her.
- 她的秀发和眼睛  - 很美的眼睛
- Her hair, and her eyes.  - Very pretty eyes.
她的背轻轻拱起 尾椎曲线毕露
The way her spine gently arches to meet the top of her tailbone.
我真想扎营住在上面 懂吗？
I just wanna pitch a tent and live in there. You know what I mean?
- 不会吧  - 你说过头了
- No.  - You're taking it too far.
你真热爱户外
Quite the outdoorsman.
我只是想说她的身体很美
I just mean she's got a great body.
- 是啊  - 知道了
- Oh, well, yes.  - Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
她是很甜美的女孩
She's a darling girl.
- 就像你 芭芭拉  - 好基因
- Like you, Barb.  - Great genes.
好的
Okay.
窈窕母女档
Two fit women.
这我再认同不过了
I'll have to agree with you there.
辣妈芭芭拉
Ol' Slamming Bod Barb.
两位美女跟两个好命鬼…
Two fit women and two lucky dudes...
和一个双插男
And one double-dicker.
好吧
Okay, well.
莱德 你哪一年从斯坦福毕业的？
Laird, when did you graduate from Stanford?
我没念那里 我高中都差点没毕业
Oh, I didn't go to Stanford, bro. I hardly even graduated from high school.
他只是谦虚
He's being modest.
他十三岁就开始帮升阳电脑写程式
He actually started writing code for Sun Microsystems when he was 13.
- 那倒是  - 跟我一样
- That's true.  - Wow, that's just like me.
我从七年级就在弗莱明公司实习了
I've been interning at the Fleming Company since, what, the seventh grade?
是啊
Mm-hmm. Yup.
未来的执行长 但你要上大学
Future CEO, but you are going to college.
- 我知道啦…  - 就像你姐姐
- I know, Dad. I know. I know.  - Just like your sister.
史黛芬 你不讶异
So, Steph, weren't your surprised
这位科技业大亨想跟你交往吗？
that this big tech mogul wanted to date you?
他自称是优步的基层工程师
He said he was some low-level programmer at Uber.
我不知道他赞助了整场活动
I had no idea that he sponsored the entire event.
所以他骗了你
So he lied to you.
我身不由己啊
Oh, Ned, I had to.
矽谷有很多拜金女
I mean there are so many gold diggers in Silicon Valley.
她们只想用鲍鲍换包包
They just wanna fuck you for your tech money.
- 注意用词 宝贝  - 小心为上
- Language, baby.  - You gotta be careful.
我一直到四月才坦白
I didn't spill the beans till April.
四月？那是八个月前吧？
April? That's eight months ago. What?
你在电话里说你们只认识几个月
Steph, over the phone, you said you've only known each other for a couple of months.
- 一开始还没认真嘛  - 才不
- It was super casual at first.  - No.
才不是这样
No, it was not.
我们第三次约会就说我爱你
We exchanged I love you's on the third date.
- 记得吗？就在我们…  - 才第三次？
- Remember? Right after we...  - The third date?
- 在伊沙兰的浴缸里爱爱后  - 不…
- Made love in the hot tub at Esalen in Big Sur.  - No! no!
- 哪里？ - 大索尔的伊沙兰
- Where, what?  - Esalen in Big Sur.
真的吗？
Really?
奈德 你别误会
Ned. Don't get the wrong idea.
那不是性 绝对不只是那样
It was not sexual at all. It was so much more than that.
抱歉 这下我听不懂了
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm confused.
你们到底有没有性交？
Did you have intercourse or not?
史考特 闭嘴
Scotty, shut it.
爸 我只是想厘清事实
Dad, I'm just trying to connect the dots here.
好吧 我们做了
Look. Yeah, we did.
但我想说的是那改造了我
But what I'm saying is I was transformed.
史黛芬就像花苞般绽放开来
Stephy opened up like a flower.
可惜你们没看到
You should have seen it.
我是不该看到 但现在有画面了
I shouldn't have seen it, but now I feel like I have.
我只是想让你爸妈知道
I just want your parents to know
你是和全心爱你的人同居
that you're living with someone who's completely devoted to you.
- 等一下  - 同居？
- Wait a minute.  - What-ing with someone?
- 你们现在住在一起？ - 对
- You say you're living together?  - Yeah.
没有 才没有呢
No. We do not.
好吧 一星期有五天
Okay, five nights out of seven.
这里有你的东西
Your stuff is here.
你不常住在宿舍
You don't really stay at the dorm.
- 你在这里有牙刷吗？ - 有
- Do you have a toothbrush here?  - Yes.
那就是同居
Yeah. That's cohabitating.
史考特 闭上嘴吃你的报纸
Scotty, stop talking and eat your paper.
爸 我们没有住在一起
Dad, we do not live together.
对 只是同居
Yeah, we're cohabitating.
[发情的水豚]
“像花苞般绽放开来”
"Opened up like a flower."
老公 我在看伊沙兰的网站
Honey, I'm looking at the Esalen website right now
那里一点都不低俗
and there's nothing dirty about it.
他们还提供瑜伽课等等的
You go up there for yoga classes and things like that.
他们等于已经同居了一年
They've been practically living together for a year.
她怎么都没告诉我们？
Why didn't she just tell us that?
毛巾在哪里啊？
Where the heck are the towels?
他还带坏了史考特
He's even affected Scotty.
到底什么是该死的双插？
What is a double dicking, for crying out loud?
她来了
There she is.
我的天 她会…
Oh, my God. Oh, yeah. She's gonna...
她最好解释这是怎么回事
She better explain what the heck is going on here.
你客气点
All right, so be nice.
说你好喜欢她超正常的男友
Be like, "Oh, my God. I love your boyfriend. He's so normal."
我行的
I'm good.
嗨
Hi.
Hi, uh...
我以为是史黛芬
I thought you'd be Stephanie.
史黛芬累坏了
Steph's super pooped.
我晚餐时的表现让我们大吵一架
We had a big fight because of the way I behaved at dinner.
别担心 我们洗鸳鸯浴 床尾合了
Don't worry, we took a shower together and worked it out.
但我溜出来看看你们
But I snuck out to have a little check in.
好的…
Okay. Well...
奈德 你要加入我们吗？
Ned, would you come join us?
我在这里就好了
I'm good here.
拜托 这是特大双人床
Oh, please. This is an Alaskan king.
空间还很多
There's so much room.
超多的
So much room.
这对我意义重大 拜托你
It'd really mean a lot to me. Please?
好吧
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
我欠你们一个道歉
I owe you two an apology.
我一紧张起来
When I get nervous
就会一直讲各种垃圾话
all kinds of crap comes flying out of my mouth
我知道这不是你们的调调
and I know that's not how you guys roll.
没错
No.
我只是想给你们好印象
I was just trying to make a good impression.
你有啊…
Yeah. Well, you did. It was...
其实你没有 不过没关系
I mean you didn't, but it's okay.
晚餐很尴尬
It was an awkward dinner.
那情况很特殊…
It was a unique situation for...
但我们就别再提了
Yeah, but let's all just move on.
好 太好了
Okay. Great.
说真的
Truth be told,
我跟父母相处的经验不多
I haven't spent a lot of time with parental figures.
你们可能不知道 我没见过我爸
I don't know if you know this, but I never knew my father.
他在奥克兰的酒吧钓到我妈
Yeah, he picked up my mom in this bar in Oakland.
他们车震后就没再交谈过了
They had some sloppy car sex, and then never spoke again.
好的
Yeah.
我跟我妈也不亲
I'm not really close with my mom, either.
坦白说 她算是个大贱货
To be frank, she's kind of a motherfucking bitch.
一句罚一块 我就发了…
If I had a nickel for every time I...
是啊
Yeah.
很遗憾听到这些
We're sorry to hear that.
真是个悲惨的故事
That's some tough stuff, pal.
是啊 真是…
Yup. That's...
真的是…
That's...
好了 时间有点晚了…
All right. Well, it's getting late, so...
是啊
Yeah.
我好爱你们的女儿
I'm in love with your daughter, dudes.
能认识养育她的人让我超嗨的
And I'm just so fucking psyched to get to know the people that raised her.
我们要照你们家的方式来过圣诞节
And we're gonna do Christmas just like you do at home.
明天晚上…
Tomorrow night,
我要为你们办一场派对
I'm gonna throw a party in your honor.
- 不用这么大费周章  - 真的不用
- Oh, you don't have to go to the trouble. You don't...  - It's not.
所有的节日狗屁都要来一回
We're gonna do all the holiday shit.
- 好  - 所有狗屁
- Okay.  - Hmm. All the shit.
奈德 我很想跟你共度男人时光
Ned, I'd love some guy time with you.
我们明天早上去走走吧？
So maybe we could take a walk tomorrow morning?
- 好啊  - 太酷了
- Okay.  - Okay, cool.
贾丝汀 奈德的闹钟要设在六点半
Justine, will you set Ned an alarm for 6:30 a.m.?
没问题 莱德
You got it, Laird.
奈德 明早的闹钟已设定在六点半
Ned, an alarm's been set for you for 6:30 en la mañana.
什么？那是谁？
What? Who is that?
那是贾丝汀
That's Justine.
她就像Siri 只是更赞
Yeah, she's like Siri, but awesome.
是“宅男行不行”凯莉库柯的声音
I got that chick from The Big Bang Theory, Kaley Cuoco, to do the voice.
小贾 快问好
J, say hi.
奈德 芭芭拉 你们好吗？
Hey, Ned. Hey, Barb. How are you guys?
- 你好  - 我的天
- Hi.  - Oh, my God.
史黛芬常提起你们 有事就叫我
Stephanie's told me so much about you. Anything you need, I'm here.
- 好的  - 谢谢你
- Okay.  - Thank you.
她…看得到我们吗？
She can't... Can she see us?
她说不能 但我觉得她可以
She says that she can't, but I think that she can.
别唬烂了 你明知我看不到他们
What the fuck are you talking about? You know I can't see them.
她很变态
She's a perv.
莱德
Laird.
总之 希望你们俩好好休息
Anyway, I hope you two have a nice night's rest.
你也好好休息
Yeah, have a good night. Great night.
- 晚安了  - 好的
- Have a great night.  - Yeah.
我觉得该给你们爱的抱抱
My instinct is to hug you right now.
- 不了  - 你不必…
- Oh. No.  - I don't think you...
没关系
That's okay. Oh.
- 我的天  - 芭芭拉
- Oh, my God.  - Barb.
晚安
Good night.
掰了
Peace.
♪ Baby, I want to trim your... ♪
♪ Beautiful Christmas tree ♪
♪ I'm gonna bring along my hatchet ♪
♪ My beautiful Christmas balls ♪
♪ I'll sprinkle my snow upon your tree ♪
♪ And hang a mistletoe on your walls ♪
♪ Baby, I want to trim your... ♪
♪ Oh, beautiful Christmas tree ♪
[杂种]
- 老婆 这里没卫生纸  - 糟糕
- Barb? There's no toilet paper.  - Uh-oh.
可以帮我拿一卷吗？
Would you get a roll for me, please?
把拔便便了？
Papa make a poopie?
对 我便便了
Yes. I made a poopie.
把拔臭臭了？
Did Daddy do a doo-doo?
老婆 你就去找卫生纸吧
Barb, just get the toilet paper, please?
好啦 你坐好 我去找卫生纸
All right. Well, you sit tight. I'm gonna go find you some TP.
谢谢你
Thank you.
当然了
Of course.
[雅虎 搜寻莱德]
花花公子
Mr. Playboy.
不可思议
Unbelievable.
这是谁？
Who is that?
长得不怎么样
She's a bit of a Plain Jane.
- 老公？ - 好…
- Darling?  - Yeah. Yup.
开个门缝 把它丢进来吧
Just, um, crack the door and toss the roll, please.
情况没那么简单
It's gonna be a little more complicated than that.
早安 奈德
Good morning, Ned.
我是古斯塔
It's Gustav.
太好了
Great.
我们这里其实是无纸住家
As I've already told Barb, we are a paperless household.
无纸什么？
Paperless? What?
是无纸住家 老公
It's a paperless house, darling.
我知道了
I got that.
那我要怎么“收拾善后”？
But how am I supposed to complete my business?
所有的日本制马桶
Well, all Japanese toilets
都有好用又舒适的洁净喷嘴
have a very effective and pleasant cleaning spray.
我非常乐意…
And I will be very happy
- 为你解说整个过程  - 老天
- to walk you through the entire process.  - Oh, God.
奈德 请看你左边的控制面板
Ned, please locate the control panel to your left.
我看到了
Okay, I see it.
控制面板上有个按钮
Now on that control panel is a button
有水柱往上喷的图案
that shows an image of water spraying up.
好 按下去就行了？
Okay. And I just push it?
对 按下去
Just press it, yes.
这是古龙水吗？
Was that cologne?
古龙水？对了…
Oh! Cologne? Oh, yes!
那是有名牌香氛的爽身粉
That is a designer-scented talcum powder.
但那按钮不该启动这功能的
But that button should not have activated that.
奈德 那是雷夫罗伦的马球男香
Ned, that is what is called Big Pony for Men by the Ralph Lauren.
我好想试试哦
I'm excited to try.
- 可以继续了吗？ - 可以
- Can we please just continue?  - All right.
- 奈德？ - 是
- Ned?  - Yes.
我要再次诚心向你道歉
I would like to apologize sincerely again.
你现在坐的是二〇一八年的款式
This is the 2018 model that you are on right now,
他们的说明书还没有英文版
so they have not yet made an instruction manual in English yet.
所以我要从这边处理 好吗？
So I'm going to take care of this on my end, all right?
你专注在你那边就好
So Ned, you focus on your end in there
我会从这里瞄准你那边
and I will focus on your end out here.
- 说的真好  - 就是这个
- That's too good.  - This is it.
这样应该行了 奈德
This should do it, Ned.
好 有运转声了
Okay. Something's whirring.
有东西在运转
Something's spinning around in there.
不 快把它关掉
No! Turn it off!
关掉…
Turn it off! Turn it off! Turn it off!
天啊
God!
惨了
Oh, scheisse!
我们遇到一些技术问题
We are having some technical difficulties.
那是阴部清洗功能
That was the vaginal cleanse.
什么清洗？
The what cleanse?
我只想要一张卫生纸
I just want a square of toilet paper.
阴部清洗
The vaginal cleanse.
我听说会很清爽 显然也很刺激
Which I hear is refreshing and apparently also very stimulating.
我听说的
Just saying.
奈德？
Ned?
你来真的？
Really?
对不起 奈德
I'm so sorry, Ned...
但我必须从里面手动重开机
but I'm going to have to manually reboot the system from the inside.
从这里？
In here?
真对不起
I am so sorry.
好吧
Fine.
有何不可？
Why not?
老婆 可以关上门吗？抱歉
Barb, would you close the door? Sorry.
这会很棒的
It's gonna be great.
奈德 我是专业人士
Ned, I am blinders.
我什么都没看到 闻到
I see nothing. I smell nothing.
- 这图案太小了  - 没错
- The print is very small.  - Mm-hmm.
不好意思
Okay, forgive me.
我看不到说明
I can't see the instructions.
好了 让我看看
All right. What do we have here?
我昨晚有点肠胃问题
I had some stomach problems last night.
我想是熊肉害的
I think it was the bear.
我保证是熊肉害的
I can guarantee you, it was the bear.
抽风机启动中
Turning on the fan.
太好了 真给力
Great. Wunderbar.
怎么样？
How'd it go?
很抱歉花了这么久的时间
I am so sorry that it took so long.
奈德 我需要你定住不动
Ned, I'm going to need you to be completely still
我们要锁定你的位置
while we try to lock in your location.
我坐在马桶上 够“定”了吧
I'm sitting on a toilet, that's pretty still.
搜寻中…
Searching, searching, und searching.
我们锁定目标了
And we have target achieved!
让水喷吧
And sploosh!
吃吧 女孩们
There you go, girls.
你养鸡？
You raise chickens?
完全放养
All free-range.
也有乳牛
Cows, too.
猪 几只羊驼
Pigs, artisanal llamas.
这里的食物都来自方圆五百码内
Everything you eat here comes from within a 500-yard radius.
我称之为“草地直送饮食法”
I call it "lawn to table eating."
它来了
There she is.
黛西
Hey, Daisy.
嗨
Oh. Hi.
去吧
Go on, get.
真高兴能跟你出来走走
So glad we're doing this, Ned.
我常听史黛芬说你的事情
I feel like I know you after everything that Steph's told me about you,
但见到本人还是不同…
but still not the same...
- 你要屈服吗？ - 去你的
- Do you submit?  - Fuck you!
- 古斯塔  - 奈德 让开
- Gustav!  - Ned, stay away!
你想打？
You wanna fight?
- 投降吧  - 不要
- Tap out!  - No!
你想投降的
You want to tap out.
好啦…
Okay, okay! Fine!
很好
Nice work!
你的反应越来越快了
And your reactions are getting quicker.
- 真的吗？ - 对
- Really?  - Absolutely.
谢了
Thanks.
抱歉 奈德 我不想让你受伤
I am so sorry, Ned. I just didn't want you to get hurt.
等等 这是《粉红豹》那套？
Wait, so you just do this Pink Panther thing?
- 粉红豹？ - 粉红豹？
- Pink Panther?  - Pink Panther?
《粉红豹》电影里的粉红豹啊
The Pink Panther from the Pink Panther movies.
卡图会攻击探长 让他保持警觉
When Cato attacks Inspector Clouseau to keep him sharp.
是很老的片吗？我没听过
Are those really old? I never heard of it.
我也不太清楚 但听起来很有趣
I'm not familiar, either, but it sounds absolutely charming.
《粉红豹》啊
Pink Panther.
电影？
The movies? Mm-hmm.
卡图是他的助手兼男仆
Cato is his assistant, his houseboy.
- 男仆？ - 这…
- Houseboy?  - Well, it's...
有种族歧视的味道
That sounds racist.
他是会叫他“黄种朋友” 不过…
He did call him "my little yellow friend." But...
莱德是大型科技公司的执行长
I'm sorry, you have to understand, Ned. Laird is the CEO of a massive tech company.
我不喜欢被保镖跟着跑
I don't like bodyguards around
我就请老古训练我 以防我被绑架
so I have Goose train me in case I get kidnapped or whatever.
对了 你的春谷道动作很扎实
By the way, your Chun Kuk Do moves were very solid.
但闪避性跑酷呢？
But what happened to the evasive parkour?
- 闪避性跑酷  - 是的
- Ah, evasive parkour.  - Yeah.
我他妈恍神了
I totally fucking spaced!
永远都有进步空间
There's always room to improve.
- 很好  - 谢了 老兄
- All right.  - Thanks, man.
你行的 兄弟
You got it, brother.
我先告退了 朋友
All right, ciao for now, you friends.
你们好好聊天吧
And you guys have a lovely chat.
奈德 来吧 去看看我的办公室
Ned, come on. I wanna show you my office.
那根本就是“粉红豹”
You know, that's like classic Pink Panther.
- 这是你工作的地方？ - 对
- This is where you work, huh?  - Yeah.
我在屋里有个处理财务的小房间
I have a den in the house where I do the financial stuff
但好点子都是在这诞生的
but this is where all the big ideas happen.
你难道不需要电脑跟…
Don't you need a computer and...
不用 贾丝汀都会记录下来
Nah. My girl Justine records everything.
对吧？
Right, J?
没错 嗨 奈德
Yep, I'm here. Hey, Ned.
你放一下昨天的录音吧
Hey, why don't you play back a blip from yesterday's session?
马上来 靠 你的云端有好多垃圾
All right, hold on. Fuck. There's so much shit up here in your Cloud.
好 我找到了
Okay, okay got it.
快想出游戏的名字 白痴
Come on, idiot, think. Names for games. Um...
猿人刺客6：卷尾猴之乱
Ape Assassins Six: Capuchin Chaos.
银背大猩猩骚莎
Uh, Silverback Salsa.
狒狒颜射
Baboon Bukkake.
妈的 烂透了
Fuck! Wow, that's awful!
烂主意
Bad idea.
为什么？
Why? Why's that? Uh...
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
颜射吗？
Bukkake?
就是状况此起彼落 让你应接不暇
Just means a lot of things are happening and you're feeling overwhelmed.
- 这样啊  - 对
- Mm-hmm.  - Yeah.
我也有颜射的经验
Yeah. I've felt bukkake before.
坐吧 当自己家 轻松一下
Grab a seat. Make yourself comf. Let's break it down.
直接躺地上是吧
Just pop down right here on the floor.
这就对了
There you go.
奈德 你跟我有很多共通点
Ned, I think you and I have so much in common.
我们看到想要的东西 就全力以赴
We see something we want and we just dive in
然后拿下它
and we take it.
你懂吗？
Know what I mean?
懂…
Yeah.
所以呢…
Which is why...
圣诞节当天…
...on Christmas Day...
我要向史黛芬求婚
I'm going to ask Stephy to marry me.
我知道你们的感情有多紧密
And I know how tight you two are.
对
Mm-hmm.
所以我真的很想…
So I'd really, really
得到你的祝福
like your blessing.
莱德
Uh, Laird.
- 谢谢你找我谈  - 当然
- Really appreciate you coming to me.  - 'Course.
但答案是不行
But, uh, the answer's no.
老兄 我好困惑
Dude, I'm so confused.
搞屁啊？什么鬼？
What the fuck? What the hell?
我跟古斯塔排练时完全不是这样
This went so much differently when I rehearsed it with Gustav.
我问你 然后你说“好 儿子”
Yeah. I asked you and you were like, "Yeah, dude. My son."
莱德 听我说
Laird. Listen to me, okay.
先不说我根本不知道你的来历
Beside the fact that I don't know you from a hole in the wall...
史黛芬还没准备要迈入这个阶段
Stephanie is just not ready for this step in her life.
我倒觉得她一直在暗示我
Oh, I'm totally getting the signals that she is.
我是她爸 我还蛮了解她的
I'm her father, I know her pretty well.
好…奈德
Okay, all right. All right, Ned...
老兄 我知道这太唐突了
Dude, I know I sprung this on you.
是我不好 我们倒带一下
My bad. Okay? Let's just back it up.
- 好吗？ - 好
- All right?  - All right.
你何不给我几天博取你的好感？
Why don't you give me a few days to win you over, okay?
等到圣诞节早上
And by Christmas morning...
我保证你会叫我“儿子”
I promise, you're going to be calling me "son."
而我会喊你“老爸”
I'm gonna be calling you "Dad".
你还是别做梦了
Don't think that's going to happen.
我敢打包票 老爸
I think it's gonna, Dad.
住口
Don't.
老爸 得了
Dad, come on.
- 别喊我爸  - 别喊你爸？
- Don't call me "Dad."  - Don't call you "Dad"?
我不是你爸
I'm not your dad.
你将来会是我岳父
I mean, you're gonna be my dad.
不…
No. No.
什么 老爸？
What, Dad?
现在你只是在胡闹
Okay, now you're playing with me.
好啦 老爸
All right. Dad.
听着 莱德
Look, Laird.
你何必在乎我怎么想？
Why do you even care about what I think?
你是史黛芬的爸爸
You're Stephanie's father.
没有你的祝福 我不会向她求婚
I'm not gonna ask Stephanie to marry me unless I have your blessing.
好吧
Okay.
贾丝汀 你有录到吗？
Justine, did you get that?
完录 一字不漏
Totes. Yeah, recorded every word.
完录…什么是“完录”？
Totes. And totes is what?
就是“完全有录到” 但用简称省事
It means totally. But totally's kind of long, so "totes" is just easier.
好 很好
Okay. Good.
- 好吧  - 好吧
- Okay.  - Okay.
- 酷哦  - 是啊
- All right, cool.  - Yeah.
但是你要答应我
But you gotta promise me
你不会向史黛芬透露求婚的事
that you won't tell Steph anything about this.
只字不提
About any of this.
相信我 我一点都不想提
Trust me, that is the last thing in the world I will do.
说真的 我要给她惊喜
For reals, dude. I want it to be a surprise.
我什么都不会说的
No word. I won't say a word.
对芭芭拉跟史考特也不能乱说
Barb and Scotty, too. No clowning.
不乱乱说
No clowning.
什么？
What?
我们打勾勾 这样我比较放心
I'd just feel a lot better about this if we pinky swore.
哦…
Oh.
- 我懂了  - 酷
- I see what you mean.  - Cool.
- 去吃早餐吧  - 好
- Go get breakfast.  - Okay.
妈的
Fuck!
你们好
Sup, guys?
- 老板  - 梅修
- Hey, boss.  - Mayhew!
♪ ...took a little longer ♪
♪ Go into the school gonna run another banger ♪
- 搞什么？ - 马上跟我来
- The fuck?  - Come with me immediately.
这里面有什么？
The hell is this room?
蓝迪 给我滚
Randy, get the fuck out.
- 是 古斯塔  - 快点
- Yes, sir, Gustav.  - Mm-hmm.
我现在好忐忑啊
I am on the needles und pins.
你快告诉我结果 不然我要爆炸了
I need you to tell me how it went right now or I'm going to burst.
- 他说不行  - 什么？好…
- He said no!  - What? Okay, okay.
那你怎么回应他？
But how did you respond?
我被捅刀了 整个慌了手脚
I was blindsided, man. I didn't know what to do.
我就挑战他
I challenged him.
- 好  - 我开始叫他爸
- Okay.  - I started calling him Dad.
- 我难过  - 干嘛啦？
- Oy vey.  - The fuck, man!
你干嘛叫他爸？你让他不自在了
Why would you call him Dad? You're putting him at unease!
你要投其所好
You have to find a way in.
为他做件真正特别的事
You have to do something for him that's truly special
让他知道你是真心诚意的
so that he knows that your intentions are pure.
老古 我不知道怎么跟他相处
Dude, Goose, I don't know how to talk to the guy.
我们好像语言不通一样
It's like we speak two different languages or something.
- 这倒是  - 对啊
- You do.  - Yeah.
他讲英语
He speaks English.
你也讲英语 和数不尽的“妈的”
And you speak English with resounding amounts of "fuck."
好啦 史黛芬也念过我
All right, Stephanie's been on my case, too.
- 对  - 我知道了
- Yes.  - I got it.
- 你懂了？ - 对
- All right?  - Okay.
- 好  - 没问题
- Right.  - All right, man.
- 很好  - 很好
- Great.  - Great.
你这巴掌真他妈的用力
You just fucking really hit me really hard.
我知道 抱歉
I know. I am sorry.
只是 莱德…
It's just, Laird...
你跟史黛芬小姐的感情
...your relationship with Miss Stephanie
非常特别 而且是认真的
is very special. It's the real deal.
- 你哦…  - 真的
- Hey.  - Yes.
我知道我付你一狗票钱
Goose, I know I pay you a shit-ton of money,
但你真是我的好麻吉
but you're my best friend.
我们的友谊无价
Our friendship is priceless.
谢了 兄弟
Hey. Thanks, brother.
好吧
Okay.
好啦 我放弃…
Okay. Ow! Mercy. Mercy.
妈的
Fuck.
兄弟 你太狂了
Bro, you're incredible.
你真有创造力
That was very imaginative
你利用感性时刻来施展攻击
how you took that tender moment and used it as your pivot to attack.
- 是的  - 非常好
- Yeah.  - Very good.
老大 我正要去看足球赛
What's up, Cheese? I'm about to go to the football game.
雄狮队赞啦
Lions, baby!
好极了 公司还好吗？
Great. How's business?
来点好消息吧
Tell me something good.
哦 呃…
Oh, uh...
我跟迪克体育用品的人谈过了
I talked to my guy over at Dick's Sporting Goods.
比那更糟
Worse.
可恶的网页图像广告
Freaking online banner ads.
不 该死 你听我说
No. Damn it. All right, listen.
我要打给速霸陆的唐密里斯
I'm gonna call Don Millis at Subaru of Southern Michigan.
听说他们可能会找新的合作伙伴
I heard a little rumor that they might be looking for a new dance partner.
唐是那个大只佬吧？
Yeah, Don, the big guy, right?
你们以前一起卖过车
You guys go back to your car selling days.
对 值得一试 听着…
Yeah. It's worth a shot. Listen...
帮我翻出他的名片 我找支笔
I need you to go in and pull his card from my rolodex while I look for a pen.
没问题 老大
You got it, Cheese. No, you got it.
[高速企业 莱德梅修]
加州那边情况如何？
So how goes it in Cali?
感觉就像来到“阴阳魔界”
It feels like we've landed in The Twilight Zone.
找到名片了吗？
Did you find the card?
[唐·密里斯]
[梅兰妮米勒]
我找到了
Yeah. I got it right here.
等等 我没地方写字
Just hang on. I have nothing to write with here.
整间屋子都没纸
This whole house is paperless.
没纸？
Paperless?
那你怎么擦屁股？
Well, how do you wipe your ass?
没得擦
You don't.
他们有日本制的马桶会…
They have these Japanese toilets that...
你是说那种要用蹲的
It's one of those little squat jobs, little squatter.
不是…算了 告诉我号码吧
No. Just... never mind. Just give me the number.
奈德 有我在
Hey, Ned, I'm here.
我能帮你记下号码
I can take it down for you.
贾丝汀 别…我可以的
Justine, please just... I'm fine.
走开啦
Just go away.
我只是想帮忙 你不用这么机歪
All right, I'm just trying to help. You don't have to be such a dick.
等等 老大 那是谁？
Whoa, whoa. Cheese, who is that?
她嘴巴真坏 是那小子的秘书吗？
She's got a foul little mouth. Is that the kid's secretary you fighting with?
不…是住在天花板上的女人
No, no, no. That's the woman who lives in the ceiling.
老大 她长什么样？
Cheese, what she look like?
- 那女人住在…  - 她住在天花板上？
- The woman who lives...  - You say she lives in the ceiling?
她是无形的声音…
She's a disembodied voice that...
算了 我之后再解释
Never mind. I'll explain later.
听起来很辣 是名人的声音吗？
The voice sounds sexy. Are they using somebody famous?
没有很有名啦 周薪几百万而已
I wouldn't say too famous. You know, million dollars a week,
只是全球最夯的影集嘛
biggest show in the world, no big deal.
- 小卢  - 她听得到我讲话？
- Lou.  - She can hear me?
我当然听得到
Of course I can hear you.
你好吗 宝贝？
How you doin', baby?
跟你讲到话就好多了
Better now that I'm talking with you.
号码给我 我现在打给他
Just give me the number. I'm calling him now.
[读取中…]
冲浪时间到啦
Let's catch some waves.
[第二关 海啸]
海啸
Tsunami.
那个人好酷
That guy's cool.
对 老古最屌了
Yeah, Goose is the best.
[莱德]
[史考特]
莱德 我老实跟你说
Laird, I'm gonna be honest with you, buddy.
好
Okay.
僧帽猴穿海滩裤是很有趣
Gorillas in board shorts is a fun touch.
- 是啊  - 这点没问题
- Yeah.  - I'll give you that.
但抵达海岸就过关 戏剧性不够
But when the only mission is to get to shore, I'm not feeling enough drama there.
你懂吗？
You know?
你他妈的对极了
You know what? You're so fucking right.
妈的
Fuck!
我们研发这掰咖鸡好几个月了
We've been developing this limp dick for months.
你来玩个五分钟 就知道问题在哪
You come and you play it for five minutes, you know exactly what's wrong with it.
你真是个犀利的小混蛋
You're a sharp little fucker. You know that?
谢谢
Thank you.
说真的 谢谢你这么说
I mean, for real, man. I appreciate it.
能被倾听真好
It's just nice to be listened to.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
有一天我会接下我爸的事业
I'm gonna be running my dad's business one day.
嗯嗯
Uh-huh.
但他根本不听我创新的想法
But he won't even listen to any of my ideas about innovation.
- 什么？ - 夸张吧？
- What?  - Right?
你是下一代耶
You're next gen, dude.
大家都知道你们会带来新点子
It's where all the new seeds come from. Everyone knows that.
我跟他说过…
And I told him that. I was like...
“爸 如果你想要我发挥潜能”
"Dad, if you're gonna unleash me to my full potentsh...
“就让我坐上桌”
"I need a seat at the table."
他就是不肯听我说
He just won't listen to me.
坐上去
Um... Get that seat!
我会坐上去的
I will get that seat.
- 你要坐上去  - 那是我的座位
- Gotta get that seat, Scotty.  - That's my seat.
- 其他人不准碰  - 没错
- Nobody else touch it.  - No.
哪里的座位？他妈的会议桌
Where is that seat? It's at the fucking table.
我会坐上会议桌
And I'm gonna get that seat at that table.
你值得一个王座 小子
You deserve a fucking throne, dawg.
- 对 铁王座  - 铁王座
- Yeah, the Iron Throne.  - Iron Throne.
- 铁王座  -“权力游戏”啦
- Iron Throne.  - Game of Thrones over here!
我要喷火 到处抓奶子
I'm breathing fire and grabbing titties left and right.
干掉乔佛里国王
Fucking King Joffrey up in this.
那些奶子是我的
Those are my titties!
- 你是继承人  - 没错
- You're the next in line.  - That's me.
好兄弟
My man.
天啊
Oh, God.
他们在帮你付学贷…
They're paying your student loans.
[负债总计 375,458.27元]
[戴尔电脑]
[新邮件]
[紧急！]
无邮无虑的邀请函
Stamp Free Invites.
[无邮无虑邀请函]
[弗莱明与梅修的佳节派对]
[晚上8点在莱德家]
[圣诞他妈的要快乐！]
老天
Oh, man.
呵…
Ho, ho, ho!
哇
Wow.
- 那是马吗？ - 是羊驼
- Is that a horse?  - That is a llama.
- 羊驼啊  - 嗨
- Oh, a llama.  - Hi.
你好
Hello.
- 我的天啊  - 乖女孩
- Oh, my goodness.  - Hey, girl.
我们那里没有这些…
We don't have those in...
爸
Dad!
你在这啊 有件事超夸张
There you are. This is insane!
你在看帐册？
Oh, you working on the books?
是啊 一点小事
Uh, yeah, you know. Just the little stuff.
我刚刚在想莱德的圣诞派对
I was thinking about Laird's Christmas party.
古斯塔让我先看了宾客名单
Gustav gave me a preview of the guest list.
那简直是矽谷A咖名人录
And, Dad, it is a veritable "who's who" of Silicon Valley power players.
泰森莫岱尔会来耶
Tyson Modell is coming!
- 他是谁？ - 什么？
- Wait, who is he?  - What?
- 他是创办“鬼聊”那家伙  - 对
- He's the kid who founded Ghostchat.  - Oh, right.
他拒绝了脸书的三兆 而且才二十四岁
He turned down three billion dollars from Facebook, and he's only 24 years old.
我要让你们坐下来聊聊
I'm gonna broker a sit-down between you two.
谢谢你提醒我要带刮胡刀
Dad, thank you for telling me to pack a blazer.
我该打领带或走商务轻便风？
Now, should I throw on a tie or should I keep it business casual?
史考特 仔细听我说
Scotty, just listen to me, all right?
这些网络公司大多建立在云烟上
Most of these Internet companies are built on smoke and mirrors.
- 什么？ - 别被拐了
- What?  - Don't get sucked in.
那整个产业都是胡扯来的
That whole industry is based on hooey.
我要教你一些观念
I'm gonna drop some knowledge on you.
爸 时代在变
Times are changing, Pops.
你眼中的胡扯未必都是胡扯
And not everything you think is hooey is hooey.
还真是深奥
Wow. That's profound.
真深奥
Profound.
而你…
And you...
就是胡扯天王
Hooey-meister himself.
你充其量只是只章鱼
You're nothing but an octopus.
臭章鱼
An octopus.
他妈的圣诞快乐
Merry fuckin' Christmas
你有什么酒？
What are you pouring?
今晚有新版解构蛋酒
We are doing a deconstructed eggnog tonight.
蛋酒 好 谢谢你
Eggnog. Yes. Thank you.
你是哪里人 老大？
Where you from, boss?
密西根
Michigan.
密西根 你在汽车业吗？
Oh, Michigan. You in the car business?
印刷业 我是奈德·弗莱明
Uh, no. Printing. Ned Fleming.
- 我是伊隆·马斯克  - 伊隆·马斯克？
- Elon Musk.  - Elon Musk?
- 对  - 特斯拉的伊隆·马斯克？
- Yeah.  - Tesla, Elon Musk?
- 是啊  - 哇
- Yeah.  - Wow.
你怎么认识莱德的？
How do you know Laird?
他在跟我女儿交往
He's dating my daughter.
糟了
Uh-oh.
- 跟你交谈很愉快  - 是啊
- Nice talking to you.  - Yeah.
什么？
What?
嗨 老婆
Oh, hey! Hi, honey!
请给我一杯白酒
Could I get a glass of white wine, please?
- 嗨 帅哥  - 嗨
- Ooh, hiya, handsome.  - Hi!
- 你真美  - 少来
- You look great.  - Oh, come on.
- 是真的  - 谢谢
- No, you do.  - Thank you.
我只是在感受节庆气氛
I'm just getting in the holiday spirit.
你跟莱德聊什么聊了那么久？
So what were you talking to Laird about for so long?
我听了梅修家族全史
I got the entire Mayhew family saga.
老天 真惨
Oh, God. I'm sorry.
不会 其实还蛮有趣的
No, no, turns out it was pretty interesting actually.
他妈妈是某间科技公司的秘书
His mother was a secretary at one of these tech companies.
想来点神户牛迷你堡吗？
Can I interest you in a Kobe beef slider?
- 好耶  - 真的食物吗？
- Ooh, yum.  - Real food?
好 我饿坏了
Yes, I'm starving.
等等 什么？
Wait, what?
天啊
Oh, God.
- 夫人要来一管吗？ - 不了 谢谢
- Ma'am? Kobe squirt?  - No, thanks.
谢谢你
Thank you.
其实味道还不错
It's actually pretty tasty.
总之 她看到年轻工程师发达起来
Anyway, she saw all these young programmers getting rich.
她就逼莱德…
So she basically forced Laird
把整个童年都花在学电脑上
to spend his entire childhood inside, learning computers.
那有点可悲吧？
I think that's kind of sad, right?
被他吞了
He ate it. Hmm.
他是章鱼
He's an octopus.
他像章鱼伸出触角纠缠我们全家
That kid is wrapping his tentacles around every member of this family.
他在玩弄你
He's manipulating you.
老公 我们该退一步想想
Darling, we need to bring this down a notch.
你觉得你在跟莱德斗争
Okay? You think you're at war with Laird.
但他没有在作战 只有你
But he's not fighting. It's just you.
我们去认识他那些可爱的朋友吧
Come on, let's go meet his friends. They look darling.
我的天
Oh, God.
JDK建置接精简型APP整个GG
Totally tanked porting the thin-client apps for the JDK build.
瞎毁？所以要重写编码？
The fuck? So you had to rewrite all the code?
对 我亲自出马
Mm-hmm. By myself.
- 那你有写好吗？ - 当然
- But did you do it?  - Oh, you know I did!
- 他们来了  - 嗨
- Hey, there they are!  - Hi.
美得冒泡
Looking like a babe.
这个小帅哥是谁
Look who's looking sharp.
- 正点  - 你们好
- Okay!  - Hello!
泰森 他们是史黛芬的爸妈 弗莱明夫妇
Tyson, these are Stephanie's parents, Mr. and Mrs. Fleming.
叫我们芭芭拉和奈德就好
Oh, no. Barb and Ned, please.
他妈的有够瞎
So it was fucked up, man.
我花了两周弄J2EE资料库
It took me two weeks on the J2EE database...
想让介面随着伺服器反应
trying to get the interface to react with the server...
我才能让容器再次运作
so I can get the containers up and running again.
抱歉 泰森 什么是J2EE？
I'm sorry. Tyson, what's a J2EE?
Java2平台企业版
Java 2 Platform Enterprise Edition.
- 你不写程式的？ - 抱歉
- Do you not write code?  - Sorry.
- 这家伙超讨厌  - 是啊
- This guy's the worst.  - Yeah.
我比较擅长人际关系
I'm actually more of a personal relations kind of guy.
像是专案管理 客户服务之类
Like account management, client services. That kind of stuff.
老兄 这小子超屌的
Dude, this kid is fucking awesome.
奈德在培育史考特接手家族企业
Yes, Ned is grooming Scotty to take over our family business.
- 没错  - 我们在密西根做印刷
- That's right.  - We own a printing business in Michigan.
真假？既然你们是做印刷的
Really? I'm sure you're familiar with those two siblings over there
应该很熟那对兄妹
since you're in the printing business.
那边的兄妹档 来见见这家伙
Yo, brother-sister act! You gotta meet this guy.
你们好
Hello!
我们是布廉和蜜西裴德曼
Hey! Blaine and Missy Pederman.
我是芭芭拉·弗莱明
Hi, I'm Barb Fleming.
- 这是我先生  - 我是奈德
- This is my husband.  - Ned.
我是史考特·弗莱明 你们好
I'm Scott Fleming. Nice to meet you.
两位应该很有名 但恐怕我们…
I'm sorry, we were told we might know you, but I'm afraid we don't.
布廉和蜜西创办了无邮无虑
Blaine and Missy started Stamp Free Invites.
好的
Oh, okay.
很好
Right.
怎么了？
What's up?
系统忘了提醒你有庆生派对吗？
Did the server forget to send a reminder for your birthday party or something?
不 他做的是真的印刷业
No, he is actually in the printing business.
- 靠  - 糟糕
- Oh, shit.  - Whoops.
没关系
No, no.
我们没害你关门大吉吧？
We didn't put you out of business or anything?
没有
No.
- 关门大吉？ - 没有…
- What? Ruin our business?  - No, no.
我们生意很好 感谢关心
We're doing quite well. Thank you.
- 太好了  - 很好 我是说真的
- Oh, that's great!  - Good for you! Honestly, good for you.
我们很爱这种街坊影印店
We love little mom-and-pop printers.
- 超励志又重要  - 没错
- So inspirational. So important.  - Mm-hmm.
我爸的公司比较像工厂
My dad has more of a factory.
不是要吹牛 但规模蛮大的
Not to brag, but we're a pretty big shop.
人们需要纸 能在上面写字的东西
People need paper. They need something to write on.
他们喜欢拿着卡片纸的手感
They love the feel of that card stock in their hands.
是啊
Yeah.
我从来没听过这种话
I've never heard anyone say that.
- 我们不知道有这种事  - 真的
- Hmm. We have not found that at all.  - Yeah. Nope.
我们应该来自不同星球
I think we come from two different worlds.
是的
Yes, we do.
你最好立马开始学编码
You better start learning code pretty fucking fast, dude.
奈德出运时
Dude, Ned was crushing it
你们俩还在抢母奶喝咧
since before you two were fighting over your mother's titties.
我妈没喂我们母乳
Our mom didn't breastfeed us.
你明知道我们有奶妈
Laird, you know we had a wet nurse.
看得出来
Oh, I can tell.
我还真听不懂你们的对话
Boy, I'll tell you, I don't know what's going on.
听拢呒
I'm lost.
- 我应接不暇  - 我也是
- I'm overwhelmed. Yeah!  - Me, too.
我完全被颜射了
There's bukkake floating all around me.
- 什么？ - 蛤？
- What?  - Hm?
什么是颜射？
What's bukkake?
莱德教我的
Oh, Laird told me.
就是应接不暇那些此起彼落的
It means when you're overwhelmed and you got too much going on.
- 这样啊  - 完全状况外
- Oh, my gosh.  - Can't figure things out.
那我简直是被颜射淹没了
Then, I'm drowning in bukkake at this point.
说真的 那是射精在脸上的意思
Okay, I'm gonna be real with you guys. It means jizz on your face.
你说啥？
I'm sorry?
颜射是指被射在脸上
Bukkake means covered in jizz.
一大堆精液在脸上
Tons of jizz, ejaculate.
通常是在多P以后
Usually after a gangbang.
没有听起来那么糟啦
Not as bad as it sounds.
对 多P的最后
Yeah, post-gangbang.
或中间 如果有人提早缴械
Or during. Depends if someone finishes early.
- 搞什么？ - 我是想保护你
- What the heck?  - I was trying to protect you, dude.
- 保护我？ - 可恶的贾丝汀
- Protect me?  - Fucking Justine.
你是想整我吧？
You mean embarrass me?
那是很感性的谈话时间
It was a really sensitive conversation.
我不想聊一群男人打枪的事
I didn't want to start talking about guys jerking off on each other.
干嘛说是应接不暇？
Why'd you tell me it was overwhelming?
是贾丝汀害的
Justine brought it up!
这个时候来看示范影片就对了
I hope this is an opportune time to show a video.
不行
It's not.
- 天啊  - 没错
- Oh, God!  - Yeah.
这是教育的时刻
Oh, and this is a teaching moment.
- 还有这个  - 我的天
- Here's another.  - Oh, my God.
- 不 史考特  - 你别看
- No. Scotty.  - Don't look at that.
你真的不用看这个
It's all good. You don't have to see this.
那是你本人吗？
Is that you?
不是
No.
天啊
Oh, my God.
♪ We alive right now, now ♪
♪ Let's get hot right now ♪
♪ We don't give a damn about money ♪
♪ We alive right now ♪
♪ All we do is party, party ♪
♪ And get hot right now ♪
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
爽啦
Yeah!
来吧 孩子的爸 你行的
Come on, Daddy. You're okay!
我需要休息一下…
Okay, I just need to take a breather. One...
♪ Do it again... ♪
♪ Lost my mind, I'm a lose it again ♪
我爱这小子
I love this kid.
我的天
Oh, my God!
♪ Rage, rage the night away ♪
♪ Forget about the money I spent today ♪
吃我一记滴滴梯 爱死你了
DDT your ass. I love you, dawg.
♪ Forget about the money I spent today ♪
爸
Hi, Pops.
- 我需要透透气  - 我陪你去
- I just need some fresh air.  - Can I come?
我们俩总是有话直说吧？
We've always been straight with each other, haven't we?
当然了
Yeah, of course.
我必须认真地问你一个问题
Okay, I need to ask you a question. And I mean this honestly.
好 什么？
Okay. What?
- 你吓到我了  - 只是…
- You're scaring me.  - No. It's just...
什么？
What?
为何挑莱德？
Why Laird?
- 说真的  - 天啊
- I mean, come on.  - Oh, my God.
- 为什么？ - 爸
- Why?  - Dad.
我们把你生得聪明又漂亮
You are so smart and you're beautiful.
你谁不拍拖 偏偏选莱德？
You could be dating anyone. Why?
- 我不懂  - 你要真相？
- I don't get it.  - You want the truth?
对
Yes.
他让我想到你
He kind of reminds me of you.
什么？
What?
- 我？ - 对
- Me?  - Yes.
好 拜托你解释一下
Okay, I need you to explain that one.
怎么会？
How?
你们都是我所认识最真诚的人
You're both the most honest and authentic men that I know.
- 只是表现方式不同  - 这…
- It comes out in totally different ways.  - Oh, well...
莱德口无遮拦
Laird has literally no filter.
我都没发现 真的吗？
I don't know that to be true. Is that right?
- 好吧  - 抱歉
- Okay.  - Sorry.
我是想帮你
Trying to help you out here.
但我发誓他有副好心肠
But I swear his heart is always in the right place.
他是很好的人
He's a very good guy.
而且我爱他
And I love him.
你爱他？
You love him?
什么？
What?
我在消化
I'm processing.
- 我们有…  - 真好笑 爸
- We had the...  - Very funny, Dad.
好啦…
Okay. Okay.
试着友善一点
Just try to be cordial.
我会的
I will. I'll try.
- 我会试的  - 试什么？
- Okay? I'll try.  - Try to what?
我会试着…
I'll try to just...
多了解那个人
...understand that person better.
来吧
Come here.
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
今晚真累人 你在做什么？
Long night. What are you doing?
放松啊
Just chilling.
那是我的衬衫吗？
Barb, is that my shirt?
不知道耶 是吗？
I don't know, is it?
要我把它脱掉吗？
Want me to take it off?
麻烦你 我只带了两件衬衫
Would you, please? I only brought two dress shirts.
我真的很不想在旅行时烫衣服
I really don't feel like ironing while I'm on this trip.
累死我了
I'm so exhausted.
好耶
Oh, yeah.
脱吧 宝贝
Take it off, baby.
快脱吧 脱掉那双鞋
Yeah! Take it off. Take off those shoes, girl.
让我看那双脚 我要看那双脚
Let me see those feet. I wanna see those feet!
你撞到头了吗？
Did you hit your head or something?
好耶 让我闻闻那鞋子
Yeah. Let me smell that shoe.
- 你不会想闻它的  - 我要闻
- You don't wanna smell my shoe.  - Yeah, I want feet!
我要袜子离开那双脚
I want those feet out of those socks.
老婆 你是怎么了？
Barb, what happened to you?
我现在正嗨呢
I am so stoned right now.
什么？
What?
对 我好嗨
Yeah, I am so baked.
我嗨翻天了
I am like super baked.
什么？你在哪里抽的？
Barb. What? Where did you?
你们离开以后 我好孤单
I was very lonely after you guys left.
我看到一个家伙拿着烟
And I saw this guy, and he had a cigarette.
我以为是那种电动的烟
I thought it was one of those electronic cigarettes.
- 那叫电子烟  - 对啦
- They're called E-cigs.  - Yeah.
没想到…
But turns out...
我在呼麻
I was vaping.
什么？
What?
我在呼麻
I was vaping.
什么啦？
What is that?
从那机器里面跑出来的是大麻
It's marijuana that comes out of some kind of machine.
- 你小声一点  - 那是合法的
- Keep your voice down!  - Ned, it's legal.
那个小可怜有睡眠呼吸中止症
Oh, this poor boy had it for sleep apnea.
- 这年纪耶？真惨  - 我要睡了
- At his age? So sad.  - I'm going to bed. That's it.
不行 等等
No, no, no. Wait!
- 老婆 我累了  - 等一下
- Barbara, I'm tired.  - Wait a minute.
我的头也在痛
And I've got a headache.
- 我们来玩一下  - 不了
- Let's play a little bit, huh?  - No, no.
看我使出我招牌的马杀鸡
I'll give you one of my patented massages.
老婆
Barb. Let's take the Little Cheese
- 让小老大出来玩嘛  - 不…
- out for a spin.  - No, no, no.
- 来嘛 露个脸  - 不要
- Come on, let me just see him.  - Don't.
- 我想看嘛  - 别帮它乱取名字
- I just want to see him.  - Don't call him that.
拜托啦
Please. Come on.
天啊 你以前很爱嗨后乱性的
Oh, my God! You used to love getting high and fooling around.
什么？不要…
What? Barb! No, Barb.
- 我们在度假  - 可能有人会经过…
- We're on vacation!  - But someone could walk...
那道门没有锁
There's no locks on the door!
什么？
What?
贾丝汀 有吻乐团的歌吗？
Justine! Do you have any Kiss?
当然有罗
Oh, hell yeah!
- 你们要做吗？ - 对
- Are you kids gonna do it?  - Yes.
- 不对  - 我们已经在做了
- No.  - We're doing it already.
- 我们正在做  - 老婆
- We're doing it right now.  - Barb!
我正在用黄金右脚做
I'm doing it with my feet. One foot.
是吻乐团 老公 你的最爱
That's Kiss! Honey, you love Kiss!
现在不要啦
But not right now.
♪ 奈德为爱芭芭拉而生 ♪
♪ Ned was made for loving Barb ♪
叫吧
Yell!
好耶…
Yeah. Yeah.
- 你看我在派对学到的  - 什么？
- Look what I learned at the party.  - What?
有个很可爱的女生一直这样
There was this real cute girl, and she was going like this.
跳很可爱的新舞步
She was doing this cute, new dance.
你的背会拉伤的
You're gonna throw your back out.
我才不会拉伤…
I'm not gonna throw my...
我要扑倒你
I'll throw you out.
- 让我上去  - 等等 你有闻到吗？
- Let me get on you.  - Wait, do you smell that?
- 我要它进来  - 什么味道？
- I'm putting him in.  - What is that scent?
它进来了
There. Oh, it's in.
- 那是什么？ - 天啊
- What is that?  - Oh, my God.
我的天
Oh, my God!
是猫王前妻的“印度盛夏”吗？
Is that Indian Summer by Priscilla Presley?
我在九十年代都喷这香水
I used to wear that perfume in the 90s.
没错 是我喷的
Yup, pumping some in.
你在同学会的脸书页面上有提到
I saw you mentioned it on your college reunion's Facebook page.
我知道你爱哪一味 奈德
I know what you like, Ned.
我知道你爱这味
Oh, I know you do, dawg.
下去吧 下去
Yeah, get in there. Get it!
- 老婆  - 大口吃
- Barb!  - Get you some!
- 快 很好…  - 好啦
- Get it! Good. Oh, that's...  - Okay.
好耶 你就快碰到了
Yeah. You're almost in there.
不对 你离它还有十五公分
No, you're, like, six inches away from it.
快点嘛 这就对了
Get in there. Yeah, that's the spirit.
- 老婆  - 好耶
- Barb.  - Oh! Yeah!
- 老婆  - 很好
- Barb!  - That's good.
很好 你开始进入状况了
Oh, that's good. You're getting into it now.
- 够了…  - 不要
- That's it!  - No!
- 不行  - 抱我…
- No, no!  - Take me! Yes! Take me!
- 我不要…  - 抱我
- I'm not...  - Take me.
我要抱你到床上睡觉
I'm taking you right to bed. That's what I'm doing.
- 下去吧  - 不要 我想做爱
- Here you go. Yes.  - No, I wanna do sex.
- 我们不会做爱的  - 可是我想啊
- We are not gonna do sex. No, honey.  - But I want to.
- 贾丝汀 关掉音乐…  - 我想要
- Justine, turn all the music off please...  - I wanna do it.
今晚别再来烦我们
...and leave us alone for the rest of the night.
我要你全放进来
It's gonna be full penetration!
你真是够了
Would you stop!
姐妹
Psst... Hey, girl.
右边第五个按钮
Fifth button from the right.
晚点再谢我
You'll thank me later.
♪ Mama, won't you please let me Mama, won't you please let me ♪
♪ Mmm... ♪
♪ Mama, won't you please let me ♪
♪ Mama do the hump mama do the hump hump ♪
♪ Mama won't you please let me do the hump hump ♪
吃吧 女孩们
There we go, girls.
你还好吗？
Okay. You all right?
还好
Yeah. Oh, man.
起来吧
That's it.
我还以为我跳得过去
Dude, I thought I was gonna make it.
我知道 你差点成功 不过…
I know. You almost did, but...
很棒的跑酷 可惜最后摔个狗吃屎
Very good evasive parkour. Yes, but the last move you ate shit.
我知道
I know.
等等让你躺下来 帮你推拿一下
I'll put you on the table later and we'll do a little adjustment.
[圣诞树]
[游击帮]
[圣诞夜特卖 七折]
跟老大出门买圣诞树
Christmas tree shopping with the Big Cheese.
你不知道这让我多兴奋
Ned, you don't know how excited I am about this.
不晓得我有没有提过
I don't know if I ever mentioned this,
我没有爸爸能一起做这些事
but I never had a father to do this kind of stuff with.
很高兴我们有机会一起出来
I'm glad we're getting a chance to hang out.
那棵不错
That's nice.
它没有让我硬起来
Uh, it's not getting me hard.
你用勃起来挑圣诞树？
You need an erection to buy a Christmas tree?
有用啊
Helps.
我想多了解你
I wanna get to know you better.
你好完美
I mean, you're so perfect.
说真的 你总是这么沉稳吗？
Seriously, did you always have your shit together?
当然不是
Oh, heck no.
我卖达特桑时被开除了
I got fired selling Datsuns.
你卖狗怎么会搞砸？
How'd you fuck up selling little dogs?
不 是达特桑
No. Datsuns.
- 那是什么？ - 是车的牌子 算了
- What's that?  - It's a car. Doesn't matter.
已经消失了
It doesn't exist anymore.
但你还在啊
But you're still here.
趋势的变化会让你紧张吗？
You ever get nervous about shifting tides?
你也知道每间公司都有起有落
Well, you know, every business has its ups and downs.
我懂 老兄
Yeah, I know it, bro.
游击帮最近不太好
Guerrilla Gang, it's been struggling a little bit.
真的？
Really?
对 这领域他妈的超竞争
Yeah, it's just a fucking tough landscape, dude.
杀不死你的事会让你更坚强
What doesn't kill you makes you stronger.
好励志 是你想出来的吗？
Chills. Did you come up with that?
不是
No, Laird.
我喷了 奈德
There she blows, Ned.
那就是我们该死的树
It's our motherfucking tree.
好啊 它跟你的麋鹿会很搭
Why not? It'll look great opposite your moose.
奈德 不是那一棵
Ned, Ned. Not that one.
是那棵
That one.
[虎虎游戏]
不对 莱德…
Oh, no. See, Laird...
它不是这店里的树
that doesn't belong to this lot.
你看 它属于…
See, it's owned by...
- 虚虚游戏？ - 虎虎游戏
- Wet games?  - Wewt Games.
给你呼呼勒 我知道那些混蛋
Like, 'woot-woot'. I know those dudes. They're dicks.
他们想抄“猿人刺客”
Tried to rip off Ape Assassins.
再说这是我们第一次共度圣诞节
Plus, it's the first Christmas with the family, dude.
要做好做满
Gotta do it right.
老兄
Hey, buddy.
怎么？
Yeah.
可以借用那把电锯吗？
Can I borrow that chainsaw?
你是说真的？
Are you serious?
对
Yeah.
妈的…
Fucking...
快啊
Come on.
你快一点啦
Will you hurry up?
我在努力了
I'm trying.
拜托 我需要那把电锯
Come on, guy. I need my chainsaw back.
等我一下
Just give me a second.
要先叫救护车还是等他锯掉手指？
Should we call an ambulance now, or wait till he loses a finger?
能借用一下吗？
Can I borrow those?
拿去吧
Have at it.
好 莱德…
Okay. Laird just...
好吧
Okay.
让我来吧
Hand it over?
- 你确定？ - 对
- You sure, Ned?  - Yup.
最强老爸出招了
Total fucking Dad move!
靠
Oh, shit!
♪ You keep on dancing and the room gets hot ♪
♪ You drive us wild, we'll drive you crazy ♪
♪ I wanna rock and roll all night... ♪
我爱吻乐团
Love Kiss!
吻乐团尚赞
Kiss, baby!
这些人好屌
These guys are awesome!
我跟史黛芬在KTV都唱他们的歌
Stephanie and I do karaoke to Kiss all the time.
我知道 所以我才放这首歌
Dude, I know, that's why I put it on!
我们的合唱还不错
And we do a pretty good job, too,
- 不是我自夸  - 水啦
- if I might say so.  - Oh, man.
- 真温馨  - 是啊
- That's cute.  - Yeah.
我一直在想我们在帐篷里的谈话
Listen, Laird, I've been thinking about our teepee talk yesterday.
我也是耶
Oh, dude, me too.
我有好多求婚的点子
I've got so many ideas for the proposal.
- 不会吧  - 奈德 你听我说
- No. No.  - Ned, hear me out.
我在想可以找固特异飞船…
I was thinking about getting the Goodyear blimp,
- 放一千只白鸽  - 等等…
- releasing a thousand doves.  - No. Wait.
莱德 等一下 好吗？
Laird, just hold on a second, okay?
- 慢下来  - 好
- Slow down.  - Okay.
我知道史黛芬真的很喜欢你
Look, I get it that Stephanie really likes you.
但是…
But... Uh-huh.
- 我就直说了  - 好
- Look. Man to man.  - Yeah.
现在不是好时机
Now is not the time.
我以为我们已经跨过那关卡了
Dude, Ned, I thought we were getting past all that.
重点不是我
No, it's not me.
而是史黛芬
It's all about Stephanie.
- 史黛芬？ - 对
- Stephanie?  - Yes.
我不确定耶
I don't know, dude.
最后这两学期会很辛苦
These last few semesters are gonna be so intense.
她毕业以后还要开始找工作
And then there's graduation, and she'll be looking for a job.
谁知道她会到哪去
And who knows where that will take her.
- 我只是…  - 好吧 奈德
- It's just...  - All right, Ned...
我不该多嘴的 但是我想让你安心
I wasn't supposed to tell you this, but I just wanna put your mind at ease.
史黛芬下学期不会回学校
Stephanie is not going back to school next semester.
什么？
What?
我知道你很震惊 不过别担心
Dude, I know you're probably shocked, but do not worry.
有个非营利组织要给她超屌的工作
She's already got this awesome job lined up at this non-profit.
是什么组织？
What organization is that exactly?
她即将成为莱德梅修基金会的董事长
She's going to be president of the Laird Mayhew Foundation.
我的基金会
That's me.
史黛芬
Stephanie!
老婆？
Barb?
楼上的都下来开家庭会议
Everybody upstairs right now, family meeting!
奈德 你要我安排会议吗？
Ned, would you like me to schedule a meeting?
你闪边啦
Oh, fuck off!
我是想帮忙 别老是这么难搞
Just trying to help. You don't always have to be such an asshole.
我偏要
Yes, I do!
- 爸  - 你惨了
- Dad.  - You are so dead.
闭嘴 我当然有打算告诉你
Shut up. Of course I was going to tell you.
我昨天逛街时就跟妈说了
I told Mom yesterday at the mall.
我只是在等好时机…
I was just waiting for the right time to bring it up
- 一直没机会  - 等一下
- and that hasn't happened.  - Wait a minute.
你知道了？
You knew?
老公 我们觉得你可能会抓狂
Honestly, honey, we thought you might freak out.
就决定等到过完圣诞节再说
So we decided to wait until after Christmas to bring it up.
不过他有说基金会的事吧？
But, okay, he told you about the foundation, right?
- 有  - 很好
- Yes.  - Yes, okay.
这是我想要你们来见莱德的主因
This is a big part of why I wanted you to come out here and meet Laird.
女儿 就算他不是个可怜的疯子
Stephanie, even if he wasn't this abject lunatic,
而且他就是
which he is,
我还是不懂为什么
I still wouldn't understand why.
你只剩两学期就毕业了
You've only got a few semesters left before you graduate.
你为什么要放弃那一切？
Why would you just throw that away?
我没有放弃任何东西
I'm not throwing anything away, Dad.
我在中美洲当义工的这一年…
The year I spent in Central America doing this kind of work,
我知道你觉得我决定得太仓促
I know you think that I'm making some rash decision
我没有
and I'm not.
我们讨论了好几个月
We've spent months figuring it out.
你隐瞒你有男友的这几个月
All the months where you didn't even tell us you had a boyfriend.
是这样吗？
All those months?
老公…
Darling...
我觉得你该听她说完
I think you should hear her out
因为听起来还蛮有意思的
because it actually sounds very interesting.
是吗？
Does it?
你愿意听我说吗？
Are you willing to listen to me?
请你说清楚
Give it your best shot.
我们打算专注在妇女健康上
The plan is to focus on women's health
进而改善第三世界的环境…
as a function of environmental change in the Third World.
- 好  - 好吧
- Right.  - All right.
当那一切失败 你会剩下什么？
And when all that goes belly-up, you know what you're left with?
- 什么？ - 大学肄业
- What?  - Being a college dropout.
- 就这样  - 你不懂
- That's it.  - You don't get it.
我不懂？
Oh, I don't get it?
没错 你一点都不懂
No, you just, like, don't get it at all.
那是什么？
Oh. What is that?
[莱德]
是刺青
It's a tattoo.
他的名字？你有刺青？
With his name? You got a tattoo?
你在身上留下印记 还是他的名字
You've marked your body with his name on it.
你看看 老婆
Look at that, Barb!
不…
Oh, no.
真是太…窝心了
That is so cute.
让我看 我想看
Let me see. I wanna see.
莱德说我该做包脖刺青
Laird's been telling me I should get a neck tat.
我知道莱德的诡计了
I see what Laird is doing here.
我看透他了
I see what he's doing.
他想挑拨我们全家
He is trying to put his imprint on this entire family.
所以我们才会有这些秘密
And that is why we've got all these secrets now.
都是因为他
And it's all because of him!
你为什么就是不肯接受莱德？
Why do you have such a big problem with Laird?
- 好问题 你知道吗？ - 什么？
- Great question. You know why?  - Why?
因为他的影响
Because of his influence,
你大学休学
you drop out of college.
因为他的影响 你“刺身”了
Because of his influence, you get a "too."
你是说“刺青”吧
Dad, I think you mean "tat."
- 当然是刺青  - 不是“刺身”？
- You definitely mean "tat." I mean "tat?"  - It's not a "too?"
- 是刺青 不是刺身  - 不是
- "Tat." No, it's not a "too."  - No.
我在脱口秀看到的
No, I saw it on Geraldo.
- 他们说是“刺身” - 好吧
- They call them "toos," okay?  - Okay.
你会从此向下沉沦
This is what's going to be your downward spiral.
你先是刺青
First you get a tattoo,
接着就会开始呼麻
then you start vaporizing.
- 什么？ - 你会呼麻
- What?  - You're vaporizing.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
就是…看似在抽电子烟
When you have... It's an e-cigarette.
但里面不是烟草或假烟草
But instead of tobacco or a fake tobacco,
里面装的其实是大麻
no, you have marijuana in that e-cigarette.
- 爸 我知道那是什么  - 好
- Dad, I know what it is.  - Yeah.
但你怎么会知道？
How do you know what it is?
因为我阅历丰富 对吧？
Because I've been around. Haven't I?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
然后你会开始用海洛因 没错
Then you go from there to heroin. Mm-hmm, that's right.
你知道沉迷毒品会有什么后果吗？
After that, after you get hooked on drugs, you know what happens next?
- 什么？ - 你会变成应召妹 妓女
- What?  - You'll become a hooker, a prostitute...
站壁的
a pimp's bitch.
你接下来就会变成那样
That's what's going to happen to you.
我清楚得很
I see it very clearly.
天啊…我还有多少时间？
Oh, my... How long do I have?
很高兴你问了 没多久
I'm glad you asked. Not long.
你再执迷不悟 很快就发生了
You keep going down this path, at this rate, not long.
你现在显然没办法听我说
You're clearly not in a place to listen to me right now.
所以我要走了
So I'm gonna go.
真谢谢你的开示
Thank you, Pops, for the guidance.
- 谢谢你  - 不用客气
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
[奈德]
♪ When the line froze, what did I see? ♪
♪ A bad mother fucker standing next to me ♪
砰
Boom!
♪ Be free like a bird so today I'ma fly ♪
♪ Bad, bad motherfucker 'til the day I die ♪
老大 让我弄清楚
Boss, let me get this straight.
你要我骇进史黛芬男友的电脑
You want me to hack into Stephanie's boyfriend's computer
看他有没有筹备基金会的记录？
and find out if there's any record of him starting a foundation?
没错
Yes, I do.
你是我的资管人员 我只能找你了
Listen, Kevin, you are my IT guy. I've got nowhere else to turn.
你知道我一直很欣赏史黛芬
You know I've always thought so highly of Stephanie.
对 她也很欣赏你
Yeah, she thinks a lot about you.
真的吗？好耶
Really? Oh, yeah.
- 我好意外  - 你听好
- That's so crazy.  - Now, listen.
我知道这家伙有钱
I know that this character has money,
不过他所谓的基金会
but there's something about this whole foundation
听起来就像胡扯的
that sounds like a bunch of hooey.
如果这家伙在胡扯 我会查清楚
If this guy's running hooey, then I'm gonna find out.
好 你得先进入他的电脑
Okay, first thing's first, Ned, you have to break into his computer
下载我寄给你的程式
and download a program that I'm gonna send you.
这就算骇客？
That's hacking?
我洗了澡 全身干干净净…
I took a shower, washing every body part...
好 我会上线
Yeah, okay. I'm getting online.
- 凯文 你在做什么？ - 宝贝？
- Kevin, what are you doing?  - Huh, baby?
我在帮奈德 跟资管有关的事
Oh, I'm helping Ned with something IT-related.
帮我向他问好
Oh, tell Ned I said hi.
好
Okay.
好 开始视讯了
All right, webcam's on.
我进到办公室了
Okay, I'm in the office.
好 到电脑前面
All right, now get in front of the computer.
好 按下空白键
All right, good. Press the spacebar.
[登入密码]
可恶 它要我输入密码
Oh, darn. It's asking for a password.
我想也是
No surprise.
很多人的密码都跟女友或老婆有关
A lot of guys have passwords related to their girlfriends or their wives.
凯文 你真天才 我就是这样
Kevin, you're a genius. That's what I have!
我就用“芭芭拉的男人一九八九” 我们结婚那年
It's "Barbsguy1989." The year we were married.
年轻一代的人比较露骨
The younger generation tends to go a little bit racier.
我要进入敏感地带了 不好意思
I'm gonna get into some sensitive areas here, so just bear with me.
史黛芬有什么外貌特征是这家伙…
We need to focus on Stephanie's more defining qualities
可能特别迷恋的？
that this guy might latch onto.
你知道我在说什么吗？
Do you understand what I'm saying?
你就直接说吧
Would you just get to it?
例如 你会说…
For example, like, would you say...
史黛芬有坚挺的胸部吗？
Stephanie has perky breasts?
- 什么？ - 好吧
- What?  - Okay.
我会说有 因为她确实有
I would say yes, because she does.
试试“史黛芬的双峰” 都小写
Please try "Stephanie's boobs" one word, no caps.
我是她爸耶
I'm her dad!
我知道你是她爸
I understand that you're her dad,
但你得用他的方式思考
but you gotta think like him.
好吗？
Okay?
[史黛芬的双峰]
不对
No.
我们得再加把劲
We're gonna have to kick it up a notch.
你说这家伙很前卫？
You said that this guy was edgy?
试试“史黛芬的紧实翘臀”
Please try "Stephanie's tight ass." Give that a whirl.
你是在整我吗 丁格？
Are you messing with me, Dingle?
我也希望我是啊
I wish I was messing with you.
我是在帮你 奈德
I'm trying to help you, Ned.
把S换成金钱符号试试看
Make the two "S's" dollar signs in "ass."
天啊
God!
光是打这些字 我就该下地狱了
I am going straight to hell just for typing this.
紧实翘臀
Tight ass.
[史黛芬的紧实翘$$]
- 不对  - 女孩们
- No.  - Hey, guys?
你们想把电影的音量调大吗？
Do you wanna raise the volume on the movie?
好啊
Okay.
我列一些项目让你输入吧
Okay. I'm just gonna list some off, you type them in.
试试“史黛芬的美乳”
All right, try "Stephanie's sweet slit."
我才不要咧
I am not writing that!
“史黛芬的粉嫩花蕾”
Okay, "Stephanie's pink canoe."
不要
No!
这对我来说可不好玩
Listen, this isn't fun for me.
[密…]
[史黛芬/]
- 我的天  - 怎么了？
- Oh, my God.  - What is it?
是密码
It's the password!
在整间屋子里唯一的纸上
The one piece of paper in the entire house.
- 是什么？ - 我要登入了
- What does it say?  - I'm gonna log it in.
“史黛芬的男人”
"Stephanie's dude."
蛮贴心的嘛
Aw, that's actually sweet.
“二〇一六”
"2016"
我们成功了
Boom! We're in.
老天
Oh, gosh!
怎么了？
What? What is it?
是史黛芬的裸照
It's a nude photograph of Stephanie.
- 我可以看吗？ - 不行
- May I see it, please?  - No.
拜托让我看啦
May I please see it?
- 我说不行  - 好啦
- I said no!  - Okay.
在浏览器里登入你的地球网帐号
Go to your EarthLink account in the web browser.
地球网…好 点下去
EarthLink, EarthLink, okay. Press.
输入密码
I give it my password.
[网络邮件]
好
Okay.
[凯文安装这个程式]
行了
Okay. I just emailed you a file.
下载我寄的档案 在桌面上开启它
Download that and open it on his desktop.
- 我们会逮到这家伙的  - 很好
- Ned, we're gonna fucking nail this guy!  - We're good!
我们是骇客
We're hacking, baby!
我们会搞死他
We're gonna nail him.
就像他搞史黛芬一样
We're gonna nail him the way he's been nailing Stephanie.
- 跟我来就对了  - 什么？
- Just come with me right now.  - What?
干嘛到办公室讲？大家都在楼下
Why are you taking me to my office? Everyone's downstairs.
- 糟糕 有人来了  - 按ESC键…
- Oh, shit! Someone's coming!  - Okay. Escape!
老天爷
Oh, God!
宝贝 圣诞夜快开始了
Baby, what are we doing? Christmas Eve is about to start.
- 你是怎么了？ - 怎么回事？
- What is the matter with you?  - What's happening?
- 我明明就说过…  - 别说话
- I specifically told you...  - Don't say anything.
我想亲自跟我爸说斯坦福的事
that I wanted to be the one to tell my dad about Stanford.
- 我知道 只是…  - 那你干嘛说？
- I know. We were just...  - Then why did you do it?
我们变得很亲近 我就说溜嘴了
We were bonding so hard, it just sort of slipped out.
你显然不懂这对他来说代表什么
You clearly have no idea what this means to him.
当我进入斯坦福 他好骄傲
He was so proud of me when I got into Stanford.
他很努力让我安心念书
He worked so hard to make it happen.
我休学等于给了他一巴掌
Me dropping out is like a huge slap in his face.
好
Okay.
我人生中从来没有像他这样的人
I just never had anyone like him in my life before.
我的天
Oh, my God!
我以为讲清楚就好了
I thought we could just talk it out.
你知道你没立场这么做吧？
You could see how that's not your place to do that, right?
也许没有
Okay. Maybe not.
当然没有
Definitely not.
你说的对 他气炸了
Okay, you're right. He was super pissed.
有时候我觉得你没办法谈感情
Sometimes I feel like you're not capable of being in a relationship.
你该面对你的父亲情结了
It's time that you get a handle on these father issues.
哇
Wow.
这是真的
That's the truth.
每次你这么一针见血
When you call me on my shit...
靠 我都觉得跟你好亲密
My God! It makes me feel so close to you.
你的诚实影响我好深
Your honesty has such an effect on me.
你现在也让我他妈的超色
You're making me so fucking horny right now.
- 什么？ - 真的
- What?  - Yeah.
你的脸让我硬
That face is boner-bait.
你看不出来我在生气吗？
Can you not see that I'm mad at you?
[他说超色吗？]
我知道 所以我才…
Yeah, I see it. That's what's...
天啊 我会被你搞疯 你都没在听
Oh, my God. You're driving me crazy! You're not listening to me.
我有在听
I'm listening.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你…
Do you...
你需要治疗
You need therapy.
- 我没有FU  - 是吗？
- Not working.  - No?
今天不行
Mm-mm. Not today, buddy.
那这样呢？
Okay. How about this?
有FU吗？
Is this working?
有一点
A little bit.
好吧 这样呢？
Okay, how about this?
又多一点点FU了
Okay. That's working a little bit more.
莱德 我爱你
Laird, I love you.
但我还在生你的气
But I'm still mad at you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 对不起  - 不…
- I'm so sorry.  - No, no!
[我想看！]
好吗？
Okay?
要啦
Yes!
不行
No!
[要啦！]
你…
You...
- 我会补偿你的  - 发生什么事？
- I'm gonna make it up to you.  - What is happening?
往后躺 我提前给你圣诞礼物
You just lie back, and I'll give you an early Christmas present.
你真是个怪胎
You are such a freak.
我知道
I know.
圣诞老人来了
Here comes Santa.
真的吗？
Oh, really?
- 呵…  - 天啊
- Ho, ho, ho.  - Oh, my God.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
有人今年很不乖哦
Somebody's been naughty this year.
[口交？]
老大？
Boss?
奈德 在吗 喂？
Ned. Are you there? Hello?
喂？
Hello? Oh.
凯文 我在 怎么样？
Yes. Kevin, I'm here. What's happening?
我进来了
I'm in.
你可以上网吗？
Do you have access to the Internet?
可以 等等
Yes, I do. Hold on.
等我一下
Wait a second.
登入你的地球网帐号
Log into your EarthLink account.
我登入了
Okay. Got it.
我现在寄些东西给你
I'm gonna send these to you right now.
- 很好  - 你死定了 梅修
- Good.  - You're done, Mayhew.
搞什么？
What the fuck?
- 怎么了？ - 我的天啊
- What happened?  - Oh, my God.
等等 什么状况？
Wait, what? What's going on?
我不知道 他有我的脸
I don't know. He has my face.
- 什么叫有你的脸？ - 我被锁住了
- What do you mean he has your face?  - I'm locked out.
我不能用电脑了
I can't use my computer anymore.
- 什么？ - 住手
- What?  - Stop that!
- 发生什么事？ - 他盯上我们了
- What's happening?  - He's onto us, Ned.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我们得停手 天啊 不要
We have to abort. Oh, God. Oh, no.
后退 混蛋 梅修在此
Move back, motherfuckers Mayhew's here
妈的
Oh, fuck!
- 他是个神话生物  - 他是什么？
- He's a mythical creature, Ned.  - He's what?
搞什么？天啊
What the fuck? Oh, God.
他把老二掏出来了
He's pulling out his penis!
天啊
Oh, my God.
他的蛋蛋深入我的数位菊花了
He's balls deep in my digital butt.
你在看A片吗？
Are you watching porn?
快关掉
Turn that off!
奈德 他在肛我
Ned, he's doing it!
玛妮 我惨了
Marnie, it's not good!
-“他妈的滚远点” - 给我关掉
- Stay the fuck out!  - Turn that off!
凯文
Kevin!
他控制了整间屋子
He has control of the house!
快过来
Come here!
- 凯文 到底怎么了？ - 我们快逃
- Kevin, what is happening?  - We gotta get out of here!
快点…
Go, go, go!
- 什么？ - 凯文
- What?  - Kevin!
凯文…
Kevin!
天啊…
Oh, my...
♪ 平安夜 ♪
♪ Silent night ♪
♪ 圣善夜 ♪
♪ Holy night ♪
♪ 万暗中 ♪
♪ All is calm ♪
[傻瓜也会C++]
♪ 光华射 ♪
♪ All is bright ♪
- 嗨  - 嘿
- Hi.  - Hey.
- 我们别吵架了  - 好
- You know what? Let's not fight.  - Okay.
很抱歉你是那样发现学校的事
I'm sorry, truly, that you found out about Stanford that way.
谢谢
Thank you.
莱德已经知道他做错了
It was not okay of Laird, and he knows that now.
但我相信这是好主意
But I'm confident this is a really good idea.
女儿 我得先告诉你一件事
Honey, before you continue, I need to tell you something.
莱德一直在骗你
Laird has been lying to you.
我试过了
I tried.
- 不是的…  - 真不可理喻
- No, no, no.  - Hey! It's unbelievable!
他有严重的财务问题
He is in serious financial trouble.
- 怎么说？ - 今天是圣诞节
- In what way?  - It's Christmas.
奈德 你错了
Ned, you're making a mistake.
他没有足够的钱能维持公司营运
He doesn't have enough money to finance his business,
- 遑论基金会了  - 你为何这么想？
- let alone a foundation.  - What exactly makes you think that?
你看到就知道了
Wait till you see this.
- 这是什么？ - 在这里
- What's this?  - Here.
你看 他的银行记录
Look at this, his own bank records.
都是赤字
All in red.
这是真的吗？
Is this for real?
对 是真的
Yeah, it's true.
游击帮这两年的生意不太好
Guerrilla Gang hasn't crushed one in a couple of years.
所以你骗我？
So you lied to me?
我即将休学…
I'm dropping out of school
创办你要出资的基金会
to start a foundation that you're supposed to be financing.
- 对  - 对
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
宝贝 基金会好得很
Baby, the foundation is all good.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
奈德 这是天大的误解
Ned, there has been a very big misunderstanding.
这只是莱德的持股
These are only Laird's business holdings.
在个人财务方面…
On the personal side...
我找了保守的私募股权投资组合
I have put together a moderate, conservative private equity sleeve
而且表现得还不错
that has been performing delightfully.
- 你说的对极了  - 是啊
- You could say that again.  - Mm-hmm.
你有照“巴菲特条款”做？
So you followed the Buffett rule?
一直都有
Always, dude.
七成股票 三成债券
70/30, stocks to bonds.
巴菲特
Buffet.
厉害
Nice.
- 你的小骇客丁格…  - 骇客？
- Your little hacker, Dingle...  - Hacker?
他钻错洞了
...was worming down the wrong hole.
- 他是说凯文·丁格吗？ - 可能是
- Does he mean Kevin Dingle?  - Probably.
不 一定是别的丁格
No, must be another Dingle.
我唯一知道的丁格是个屎蛋
Only dingle I know of is the berries on the butt.
你到底有多少钱？
Look, how much money do you have?
- 你不用回答这个  - 他非答不可
- Babe, you don't have to answer this.  - Yes, he does.
好吧 我全招了
Fine! Full disclosure.
很糟
It's bad.
我只剩九千七百万
I'm down to my last 97 million.
莱德
Laird.
是一亿九千七百万
197 million.
砰
Boom.
他还真是入不敷出
He's just barely scraping by.
你只需要问我就好
All you had to do was ask me.
各位 来首快板的《装饰大厅》
Gentlemen, I need Deck the Halls, allegro, now.
♪ 用冬青树枝来装饰大厅 ♪
♪ Deck the halls with boughs of holly ♪
奈德 秉着节日精神…
Ned, it's the holidays
我想我们该从头来过
and I think we should start over.
这是给你的
So this is for you.
这是什么？
What is it?
你会喜欢的小礼物
It's a little stocking stuffer. I think you'll like it.
手机？按下按钮
A phone? Press the button.
[购买合约 弗莱明公司]
是我在大急流城的银行传来的
This is from my bank in Grand Rapids.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
- 谁来解释一下？ - 史黛芬…
- Someone fill me in here.  - Well, Steph...
我买下你爸的公司了
I bought your father's company.
算是啦
Sort of.
我买下你所有的债务 当作礼物
Ned, I purchased all your debt as a Christmas present.
搞什么？
What the fuck?
- 你这个混蛋  - 什么？
- You son of a bitch.  - What?
我是为你好 免得你破产
Dude, I'm trying to be nice, so you can avoid bankruptcy.
是“第十一章”吗？我不想听到那个字
Are you guys talking Chapter 11? I don't even wanna hear that term.
各位 快开始唱“圣诞铃声”
Okay, gentlemen, I need Jingle Bells, and step on it!
你居然没告诉我们这件事
I can't believe that you didn't tell us about this.
不 我只是…
What? No, it's just...
最近的生意不太好
The business has been running a little rough lately.
我已经在谈新生意了
I'm already working on a new deal right now.
- 你也不知道？ - 没错
- So you had no idea?  - No.
你怎么会知道这件事？
How the hell did you know about this?
因为贾丝汀
It was Justine. Oh.
对 是我
Yeah, it was me.
她播了你之前跟别人交谈的录音
She played me back a little bit of a conversation you had the other day...
叫小卢的家伙
with a guy named Lou.
我当然得帮忙
Of course, I had to help.
奈德 很抱歉我越线了
Ned, I'm sorry if I overstepped.
是啊
Yep.
但我真的很担心你
But I was really, really worried about you.
她认真的 不是乱说
She was. No clowning.
你不用有压力
And just so you don't stress,
你一样还是老大
you're still gonna be the Big Cheese, dude.
我打算当个隐形的业主
I plan on being a very hands-off owner.
你怎么说 伙伴？
So what do you say, partner?
- 奈德 你…  - 搞什么？
- Ned, what are you...  - What the fuck?
爸 你干嘛这样？
Why would you do that, Dad?
爸
Dad!
去你的 纸片人
Fuck you, paper man!
毁了
Oh, scheisse.
奈德 对不起
Ned, I'm sorry, bro.
你还好吗？
Are you okay? Oh, man.
是训练造成的反射动作
My training, it just takes over.
现在大家都很激动
Everybody is feeling a lot of tension.
- 冷静点  - 爸
- Calm down.  - Dad!
或是用iPad砸别人的脸
Or we can hit people square in the face with an iPad.
脱离战斗 快跑
Disengage. Disengage and run!
那也太酷了吧
Dude, that was kind of cool. You gotta be honest.
奈德 我爱你 我只是想帮忙
Ned, I love you. I was just trying to help.
- 快脱离  - 老公 放开他的蛋蛋
- Laird, disengage him!  - Ned, let go of his balls!
莱德 闪避性跑酷…
Laird! Evasive parkour!
莱德 快跑
Laird, get away!
闪避性跑酷 快蹬墙
Evasive parkour! Do the wall pop!
蹬墙
Wall pop!
老古 你有看到吗？
Goose! Did you see that?
蹬得好 你终于用核心肌群了
That's right! Because you finally engaged your core!
给我下来
Get down here!
感觉是不是很不一样？
You see the difference of the feeling? How it feels differently?
我知道…
I know!
- 天啊  - 老天
- Oh, my God!  - Oh, my God!
- 别吸气 我来了  - 史考特 不…
- Don't breathe in. I'll save you, brother!  - Scotty, no! Scotty!
不行 儿子
No, honey!
我来救你了 莱德
I'm here to save you, Laird!
儿子 小心
Scotty, watch out!
莱德 你没事吧？
Laird! You okay?
没事
Yeah!
- 太好了  - 你没事
- Fantastic!  - You're okay.
- 你没事  - 等等 史考特呢？
- You're okay.  - Wait. Where's Scotty?
史考特 天啊
Scotty! Oh, my God.
- 史考特  - 他在麋鹿底下
- Scotty!  - He's under the moose!
他在麋鹿底下
He's under the moose!
史考特
Scotty!
靠北
Oh, shit.
他妈的麋鹿蛋蛋在我嘴里
These fucking moose balls are in my mouth.
靠 它在蛋洗你的脸耶
Oh, shit, he's teabagging you, bro!
我帮你
I got you.
快过来…
Come here. Come here.
天啊 没事了
Oh, my God. It's okay.
没事了
It's okay.
女儿 很抱歉情况变成这样
Honey, I'm so sorry it turned out this way.
我也是
Me, too.
我到家再打给你
I'll call you when I get home.
好好安慰史考特
Okay. Good luck with Scotty.
- 谢谢你  - 是啊
- Thank you. I'll need it.  - Yeah.
女儿 我从来没…
Steph, listen. I never...
我听够了 祝你旅途平安
I'm done listening. Have a safe flight.
- 姐 再见  - 再见 史考特
- See you, sis.  - Bye, Scotty.
我居然要回去用卫生纸了
Can't believe I have to go back to toilet paper.
唐密里斯 圣诞快乐
Hey, Don Millis. Merry Christmas, sir.
你也是 不好意思在圣诞节打来
You too, Ned. Look, I hate to call on Christmas.
小事一桩
Oh, don't worry about that.
昨天跟你叙旧很开心
It was great catching up yesterday
我想尽快把决定告诉你
and I wanted to ring you as soon as we made a decision.
好的
Okay.
我跟大家讨论过你的提案
I talked with the group here about your proposal
我们实在无法参与
and we just can't go for it.
很抱歉 兄弟
I'm sorry, pal.
真的很感谢你给我们的友情价
We really appreciate you offering us such a sweetheart deal.
但我们现在的印刷量不多
But fact is we 're just not doing a whole lot of printing these days.
- 你也知道  - 对
- You know how it is.  - Yes.
- 世界不同了 对吧  - 对
- It's a whole new world, right?  - Yes.
当然
Sure is.
我是很希望能跟你合作的 老大
I sure wish we could've done business, Cheese.
好吧 听着…
All right, listen, um,
看来我无法让你改变心意了
if you're sure I can't change your mind there, Don.
恐怕是如此
Yeah, unfortunately not.
好吧…
Okay. All right.
- 祝你假期愉快  - 你也是
- You have a happy holidays.  - You, too, Ned!
代我问候芭芭拉和孩子们
Best to Barb and the kids.
抱歉 奈德？
Excuse me, Ned?
你的班机一小时后就要起飞了
I'm sorry to bother you, but your flight leaves in an hour.
♪ Must seem strange to you, my friend ♪
我会想你的
I'll miss you.
♪ Some things are always heaven sent ♪
♪ The more you want, the harder it gets ♪
♪ The more you let go, the more you get ♪
♪ It's a crazy... ♪
♪ ...beautiful life ♪
♪ Some things make sense and you don't know what ♪
♪ It's a crazy beautiful life ♪
欢迎回来 弗莱明一家人
Welcome home, Flemings!
- 小卢 怎么…  - 你们一定很冷
- Lou, what...  - You guys must be freezing.
快进来 东西给我 老大
Come on, get in here. Let me get that. Come on, Cheese.
- 怎么回事？ - 芭芭拉
- Lou, what's going on?  - Barbara, hey.
嗨
Hi.
- 你气色真好  - 来了 圣诞快乐
- Barb, you look great.  - There they are!
圣诞快乐…
Merry Christmas!
哇
Wow!
小卢 我有传讯息说要跟你谈谈
Um, Lou, I texted you that I needed to talk to you.
这到底是…
I mean, what's...
少来了 你们有听到吗？
Come on, you hear this guy?
银行那个汉克鲁斯
Hank Rouse from First National
一早就留言道贺梅修那笔交易
shot me a congratulatory voicemail this morning about the Mayhew deal.
你办到了 老大
You did it, Big Cheese!
你创造了圣诞奇迹
You pulled off the Christmas miracle.
- 老大…  - 老大…
- Cheese, Cheese, Cheese!  - Cheese, Cheese, Cheese!
芭芭拉
Barb!
史考特
Scotty.
为了表达我们对你的感激
Ned, as a little token of our appreciation,
我们合资买了东西给你
we all chipped in and bought you something
我们很确定你没有这玩意
that we're pretty sure you don't own.
你们太客气了
You shouldn't have.
打开吧…
Open it. Yeah.
对 打开看看
Yeah, right there.
是iPad
It's an iPad.
按下那个Home键
Hit the home button right there.
好
Yeah.
绘图部的人发挥了一点创意
We had a little fun with that down in Graphics.
图片是从史考特的脸书抓的
I got the images off Scotty's Facebook page.
他看来很正直 就像年轻时的你
He looks like a stand-up guy. Like a younger version of you, Ned.
快致词
Make a speech!
对 快致词
Speech! Oh, yes, speech!
致词…
Speech, speech, speech.
那是什么？
The heck is that?
喷射机跟直升机？这是哪里？
Laird, a jet and a helicopter? Where are we?
等等 宝贝 快到了
Hang on, babe. Almost there.
- 等一下  - 梅修
- One second.  - Mayhew!
- 你们先等一下  - 去里面拿件外套
- Guys, stay here for a minute.  - Honey, go inside and get a jacket.
- 那是梅修  - 就是他？
- That's Mayhew.  - Is that the guy?
莱德
Laird!
我们在哪里？
Where are we?
怪怪的 好像格雷的五十道阴影
That looks weird. It's kind of Fifty Shades of Grey-ish.
- 冷吗？ - 是啊
- Cold?  - Yeah.
来吧
And here we go.
惊喜
Surprise!
女儿
Hi, honey.
登登
Ta-da.
- 你带我回家？ - 对
- You brought me home?  - Yeah.
没先跟我说？
Without telling me?
我是违反了神秘约会的规定…
I realize I violated the sanctity of mystery date
但今天应该是合家团圆的日子
but I just thought the family should all be together today.
你没有资格这么做
Okay, that wasn't your place to do that, hon.
女儿 我知道…
Steph, I know,
但今天是圣诞节
but it is Christmas.
- 很高兴能看到你  - 这不是她要的
- And we're glad to see you.  - This isn't what she wanted.
确实不是
No, it's not.
我本来希望我们都能在加州过节
What I wanted was for us to spend Christmas in California together
结果搞得一塌糊涂
like I planned, before everything went to shit
因为你只想到你自己
because you made it all about yourself.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
你们俩都是
You both did.
- 我？ - 对
- I did?  - Yes!
你们两个白痴以为我是你们的财产
You idiots think you can pass me back and forth
可以传来传去的吗？
like I'm your property or something?
我受够了
I'm done.
这是史上最烂的圣诞节
This is the worst Christmas ever.
- 女儿  - 乖女儿
- Steph.  - Steph. Honey.
我想她气炸了
I think she's pissed.
对 她气炸了
Yeah, she's pissed.
靠
Shit!
我只是觉得你们今天应该在一起
I just thought that you guys should be together today.
好吧 交给你了
All right. Well, I'll leave you to it.
圣诞快乐 奈德
Happy holidays, Ned.
你也是 莱德
You too, Laird.
莱德
Uh, Laird.
你故意慢慢走是因为你不想走吧？
You're doing a "I'm gonna walk away slowly "'cause I really don't wanna leave" walk.
也许吧
Maybe.
过来
Come here.
发生什么事？你没有求婚？
So what happened? You didn't propose?
我怎么能求？
How could I?
我们打过勾勾了
I never got your permission
我没有你的允许就不能开口
and we pinky-swore I wouldn't ask without it.
你真是个奇葩
You are remarkable.
你没办法骗人吧？
You don't have a gear to be dishonest, do you?
看来是不行
Guess not, dude.
你不需要我的允许来向史黛芬求婚
Laird, you never needed my permission to ask Stephanie to marry you.
但若你把它看得这么重…
But if it still means anything to you,
我祝福你们
you have my blessing.
真假？
For reals?
我没在乱说
No clowning.
哇
Whoa.
不过史黛芬是对的
But, Laird, Stephanie's right.
这应该由她来决定
It's up to her. It's always been up to her.
不是我们
Not us.
我一直到现在才了解
It just took me a while to realize that.
好中肯
It's so true.
我们真是混蛋
Dude, we were such jerks.
是啊
Yeah.
我咬了你老二
I bit your dick.
热狗加蛋
Shaft and balls. Oh.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我也很对不起
I'm sorry, too, dude.
听着 如果你想向史黛芬求婚
Look, Laird, if you wanna ask Stephanie to marry you
时机一来 就问她吧
when the time is right, just do it.
好 那我可以现在问吗？
Okay. Is it cool if I do it right now?
因为我想说可能会成功…
Because, uh, just in case it worked out
就叫老古在直升机里塞了一堆白鸽
I had Goose put a shit ton of doves in the helicopter
我还有另外两个惊喜
and I have a couple other surprises.
莱德 你决定就好
Laird, this is totally your call.
但我可以给点建议吗？
But can I give you some advice?
当然了
Dude, please.
- 我现在他妈的超紧张  - 好…
- I'm so fucking nervous right now.  - All right, look...
史黛芬不在乎华而不实的东西
Stephanie doesn't care about all the bells and whistles.
你知道她的
You know her.
她在乎的是你
She cares about you.
她爱你
She loves you.
你就单膝下跪
So you get down on one knee
对她说出你的肺腑之言
and you speak to her from your heart.
这个你最会了
That's what you're best at.
是不是 贾丝汀？
Isn't that right, Justine?
我完全同意
Totally agree.
哇靠
Holy shit.
我第一次来密西根 冷死我了
My first time in Michigan. It's cold as balls here.
是啊
Yeah.
他妈的太赞了
Dude, that's fucking great!
奈德·弗莱明风格
Do it Ned Fleming style.
老派做法
Old school!
水啦
Fuck yes.
好吧 听着…
Okay. Well, look...
我会想办法让她出来
I'll go in there and see if I can get her to come out.
好
Okay.
- 祝你好运  - 谢了
- Good luck.  - Thanks.
答应我一件事
Hey, promise me one thing.
你会好好待她
You will treat her well.
我会把她当作屌他妈的女王
Dude, I'm gonna treat her like a motherfucking queen.
我接受
I'll take that.
好
Okay.
古斯塔 改变计划
Gustav, change of plans.
我们要求婚 其他的都不要
We're go on the proposal. No go on all that other shit.
讯号不太好 你说要按计划进行？
I have only one bar. You're saying we are a go, yes?
不 不要
No. No go.
只要求婚 其他的不要
Go on the proposal, no go on the shit.
莱德 你是说“不要”
Laird, are you saying it's a no go
还是“不 要”？
or are you saying, "No. Go."?
夭寿哦 老古
God damn it, Goose.
你害我他妈的更紧张 闭嘴啦
You're making me fucking nervous. Just shut up.
抱歉 祝你好运
Oh, I'm sorry. Good luck.
对了 记得要呼吸
Oh, and by the way, please, Laird, breathe.
好
Okay.
也别骂脏话
And no cursing, okay?
靠 你说的对
Fuck, you're right. Good call.
嗨
Hi.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道我在加州让你失望了
I know that out in California I disappointed you
我很难过
and that kills me.
我真的很抱歉
And I'm really sorry.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry, too.
我不该要你来 害你手足无措
I threw you in the deep end out there. I should've never asked you to come.
我是说真的…
Honestly. No.
不 你没有做错事
No, you didn't do anything wrong.
- 我在想什么啊？ - 是我不好
- What was I thinking?  - It was me.
只是 当我们去莱德家
It's just that, when we got out to Laird's...
我觉得我好像不认识你了
I just didn't feel like I knew you anymore
我吓坏了
and I got scared.
然后我就抓狂了
I just went crazy.
我还是我
This is me.
我很好
I'm doing good.
爸
Oh, Dad.
天啊
Oh, my God.
听着 我忘了…
Okay, look. I forgot...
- 天啊 他还在外面  - 我知道
- Oh, God. He's still out there.  - I know.
只穿背心和围巾
In a tank top and a scarf.
- 亏他还知道要来密西根  - 是啊
- And he knew we were coming to Michigan.  - Yeah.
- 他干嘛不进来？ - 他有事要问你
- Why doesn't he just come inside?  - He has to talk to you about something...
他想向你道歉吧
He kind of wants to make things right with you.
- 是吗？ - 对
- Oh, does he?  - Yeah.
如果你能给他一个机会就好了
I think it'd be cool if you gave him a chance.
你要我给莱德机会？
You want me to give Laird a chance?
我只是觉得如果你给他机会
I thought that if you saw fit to give him a chance...
会蛮酷的
I thought that it'd be cool.
就这样 你说呢？
That's all. well?
- 嗨  - 嘿
- Hi.  - Hey.
什么事？天啊 外面好冷
What's going on? Oh, my God, it's cold out here.
我知道你很怒 但请你听我说
I know you're pissed, but just hear me out.
- 可以进去说吗？ - 不行
- Can we talk inside?  - No.
- 天啊…  - 你看
- Oh, my...  - Look.
我的天 好浪漫
Oh, my God. It's so romantic.
- 我跟他说简单就好  - 宝贝女儿
- I told him to keep it simple.  - Oh, our little girl.
他会单膝下跪 一切从简
He's gonna get down to his knee and keep it real simple.
你怎么知道？
How do you know all this?
我有给他一点提示
I gave him a few pointers. Oh.
这是我这辈子最快乐的一年
This has been the happiest year of my life.
飞吧 快…
And fly! Go, go, go! Go!
我的天
Oh, my God.
老古 该死 我说不要…
Goose. God damn it. I said no go! No go!
- 老天…  - 天啊 哇
- Oh, my...  - Oh, gosh. Wow.
- 他干嘛那样？ - 真聪明
- Why did he do that?  - Smart boy.
真是屎从天降
Absolute fucking shit fest.
宝贝 对不起
Babe, I'm so sorry. Uh...
史黛芬·弗莱明…
Stephanie Fleming...
- 你愿意…  - 你在求婚吗？
- will you...  - Are you proposing?
是啊
Yeah.
我爸知道吗？
Mmm-hmm. Did my dad know about this?
对 他一到加州 我就问过他了
Yeah, I asked for his blessing that first morning back in Cali.
我的天
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
难怪他那么暴躁 你哦…
No wonder he acted so crazy. Honey.
对 他变得不太理智
Yeah, that's why he was a little out of whack.
我们本来能好好过节的
Yeah, we could have had a really nice holiday.
我知道 但现在都没事了
I know. But we're all good now. Okay?
这事很重大
This is a lot.
- 我的天  - 史黛芬·弗莱明…
- Oh, my God.  - Stephanie Fleming...
是戒指耶
That's a ring.
老古 不要
Goose! No!
上吧…
And, go! Go, guys! Go, go, go!
史黛芬
Stephanie!
天啊
Oh, my God.
莱德 吻乐团怎么在这里？
Laird, what is Kiss doing here?
这个嘛…
Um, well...
- 那是…  - 哇
- Is that...  - Whoa!
他找了模仿的乐团
He got look-a-likes!
不是模仿的 那是吉恩跟保罗
Those aren't look-a-likes, Ned. That's Gene and Paul.
是吉恩跟保罗…
It's Gene and Paul! Gene and Paul!
我的老天爷
Oh, my God! Oh, God!
吻乐团在我们前院
Kiss is in the front yard!
♪ 今晚 ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ 我要把一切奉献给你 ♪
♪ I wanna give it all to you ♪
♪ 在黑暗中 ♪
♪ In the darkness ♪
我本来有更缜密的求婚计划
Originally, I had this more elaborate proposal plan
但你爸超赞 他建议我别用
but your dad gave me this awesome advice and told me not to do it.
不过我知道你很爱他们的音乐…
But they're here, and I know how much you love their music, so...
什么？嗨
What? Hi.
♪ 我是为了爱你而生 宝贝 ♪
♪ I was made for lovin' you, baby ♪
♪ 你是为了爱我而生 ♪
♪ You were made for lovin' me ♪
♪ 我无法… ♪
♪ And I can't get... ♪
他还在求婚吗？
Is he still proposing? What's...
他们停止演奏了
They've stopped playing now.
- 他叫奈德  - 老天 他们…
- His name's Ned.  - Oh, my God, are they...
什么？
What?
- 他们会进来…  - 我的天
- Are they coming in the...  - Oh, my God.
- 他们上了人行道  - 他们要进来了
- They're coming up the sidewalk!  - They're heading in!
- 他们要进我们家了  - 老天
- They're coming in our house!  - Oh, my God!
大家自然一点…
Everybody act natural! Act naturally!
我得重新装潢屋子
I have to redecorate the house!
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
Uh, hi.
- 我是奈德  - 你好
- I'm Ned.  - Hey, Ned.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi!  - Hi!
我内人 芭芭拉
This is my wife, Barb.
我们的朋友 小卢跟派蒂
This is our friends, Lou and Patty.
我是小卢
It's Lou.
真高兴看到你们
So excited you're here.
我得告诉你 我们是头号歌迷
I gotta tell you. Uh, we are huge fans.
我们加入“吻之军团”有三十年了
We've been members of the Kiss Army for, like, 30 years now.
第一次约会就是看“疯狂夜”巡回
Yeah. Our first date was the Crazy Nights Tour.
对 那真是疯狂
Yeah! And, boy, was that crazy.
疯狂
Crazy.
你们有上床吗？
Did you get laid?
我有帮他打手枪
I gave him a handjob.
史考特
Scotty.
真开心 但你们有自助吧吗？
I'm having an awesome time, but are you having a buffet here?
天啊 我在想什么？
Oh, my God. What was I thinking?
- 你们饿了吗？ - 饿扁了
- Are you hungry?  - Starving.
老天 我们真是太失礼了
Oh, God, of course! Where's our manners?
什么烂主人嘛
We're terrible hosts.
帮他们拿吉他 斧头给我吧
Let's get those guitars, guys. Come on, let me get that axe.
- 看我多紧张  - 吻乐团在我们家耶
- See my body?  - Wow! Kiss is in our house!
是啊 我现在超兴奋
Yeah. I'm Kind of juiced up a little bit.
我差点忘了他们
Oh! I almost forgot about them.
- 这个嘛…  - 甜蜜的一对
- Well...  - The happy couple.
恭喜你们
Congratulations.
她拒绝了
She said no.
抱歉 什么？
I'm sorry, what?
她拒绝了
She said no.
我…
Well...
宝贝
Honey.
你想娶我
I'm so flattered
让我受宠若惊
that you wanna marry me
但我还没准备好
but I'm not ready for that.
而且我要念完大学
And I'm gonna finish school.
为了我自己
For me.
因为那是我要的
Because that's what I wanna do.
懂吗？
Got it?
真聪明
That's really smart.
只是 我的大计划…
It's just, I had this big plan
终究没成功
and it didn't work out.
这就是人生 小子
Yeah. Well, that's life, pal.
你说得真好
That is so well put, Ned.
真的超聪明的
It's really, really smart.
是你想出来的吗？
Dude, did you come up with that?
你说“这就是人生”？
The words, "That's life?"
奈德 你真的好有智慧
Ned, you're so full of practical wisdom...
我只是很期待能成为你的女婿
I was just really looking forward to you being my father-in-law.
我又没有要跟你分手
I'm not breaking up with you.
没有吗？
You're not?
没有
No, honey.
我还是你的女朋友
No, no, no. I'm still your girlfriend.
我们还在一起
We're still together.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God!
过来啦
Come here.
[固特异]
[史黛芬 嫁给我！]
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
- 奈德  - 嘿
- Ned.  - Hey.
你的员工好酷哦
Dude, your employees are so cool.
确实如此
Yeah, they are.
也许我不该那样介入…
Maybe it was wrong of me to interfere like that,
但你何不让我救你的公司？
but why don't you let me save your company?
我不能那么做
No, Laird, I can't.
旧的模式已经不适用了
That old model doesn't work anymore.
我猜…
I guess... I don't know.
我之前只是不想承认吧
I guess I just didn't want to believe it.
但既然你提起了
But since you mentioned it...
我想要你听听我的点子
I do have a business idea I wanna run by you.
老兄 放马过来
Dude, elevator pitch me!
好
Okay.
不 等一下
No, hold on.
这不是我的点子 你等等
This wasn't my idea at all. One second.
- 史考特 过来  - 什么事？
- Scotty, come here.  - Yo, what's up?
- 过来  - 好
- Come here.  - Yeah?
把你在飞机上说的点子告诉莱德
I want you to tell Laird about the business idea you mentioned on the plane.
- 说吧  - 真的吗？
- Go ahead.  - Wait, really?
对
Yeah.
就叫你坐上桌了 小老弟
Told you to get that seat at the table, bro.
没错 爸 他跟我说…
You did. He told me, Dad. He was, like...
“你要坐上桌” 我终于办到了
"You're gonna get that seat." I can't believe I finally got the seat.
龙跟奶子 宝贝
Dragons and titties, baby.
龙跟奶子
Dragons and titties!
喷火吧
Breathe that fire.
好好享受
Get up in there.
享受那些奶子
Get up in those titties!
我要得到那些龙
Gonna get those dragons.
爸…
Dad...
史考特
Scotty!
别玩你爸的奶了 快做简报
Stop motorboating your dad, and elevator pitch me.
抱歉
Sorry. Uh...
莱德 我对你的马桶念念不忘
Laird, I can't stop thinking about your toilets, dude.
- 我的马桶？ - 对
- My toilets?  - Yeah.
那股清爽感 香氛爽身粉
The fresh feeling, the scented talc.
我在想 如果控制板有英文
I was thinking if you can get the controls in English
售价再降低一点
and maybe lower the price point a little bit,
美国就成了我们全新的市场
we could have a potentially untapped market here in America.
- 靠  - 对吧？
- Shit.  - right?
我们还能找日本制造商谈价钱…
And look, we can contact a Japanese manufacturer
儿子 恕我直言 那太瞎了
No, Scotty. Pardon my French, but fuck that noise.
- 喔  - 听着 这里就有工厂
- Whoa.  - Listen. We have a factory right here in Grand Rapids
还有三十七个最棒的员工
with 37 of the best employees you're ever gonna want.
我们自己做吧
Let's build our own.
- 水啦 奈德老大  - 好耶
- Hells yes, Grateful Ned!  - Yeah!
砰
Boom!
抱歉 没事
Okay, sorry. Yeah.
♪ 天使初报圣诞佳音 ♪
♪ The first noel the angels did say ♪
♪ 先向田间贫苦牧人 ♪
♪ Was to certain poor shepherds In fields as they lay ♪
♪ 牧人正当看守羊群 ♪
♪ In fields where they lay keeping their sheep ♪
♪ 严冬方冷长夜已深 ♪
♪ On a cold winter's night that was so deep ♪
♪ 欢欣 欢欣… ♪
♪ Noel, Noel, Noel, Noel ♪
结果这个圣诞节还蛮酷的吧？
It turned out to be a pretty cool holiday after all, huh?
是啊 儿子
It did, son.
老兄
Dude.
什么？
What?
你果然在圣诞节叫我“儿子”了
Told you you'd be calling me "son" by Christmas.
那只是个比喻
That's just a figure of speech.
是啊 老爸
Sure, Dad.
♪ Merry Christmas, I don't want to fight tonight ♪
大家好啊 是我 古斯塔
Hello there, you gang! It is I, Gustav.
真高兴看到你们
It's so great to see you!
你们觉得我的新胡子如何？
Hey, what do you think of the new facial hair, huh?
我现在都在密西根 所以…
I'm based in Michigan now, so you know...
现在都走中西部大力士风
I'm trying to do this whole kind of Paul Bunyan, Midwestern thing.
我想留满一点
I wanted to fill it all out.
[弗莱明公司]
[成立于1991年]
史考特 莱德和奈德把印刷公司…
So Scotty, Laird, and Ned took the printing company...
[弗莱明·梅修马桶]
变成一间马桶工厂
turned it into a toilet factory...
而且状况极佳
and it's going great!
马桶既省水又环保
The toilet is water efficient und eco-friendly.
是最尖端的科技
It's state of the art.
他们发明了马桶界的特斯拉
I'm telling you, they have invented the Tesla of toilets!
[成立于1991年][马桶界的特斯拉–高速企业]
太厉害了
It's amazing.
芭芭拉确保它们都有阴部清洗功能
Barbara has made sure that each toilet has a state of the art vaginal cleanse.
你们懂我意思的
You know exactly what I'm saying.
每个款式都有贾丝汀 智慧马桶嘛
Every single model comes with Justine. Talk about a smart toilet.
她知道你需要的是小水花…
She knows if you need a little sploosh
还是赌城那座大喷泉
or if you actually need the fountains of the Bellagio up there.
史考特终于坐上桌了
Scotty has finally got his seat at the table.
太美了
It's beautiful.
他有点太迷恋龙 奶子跟奶波浪
He went a little too far with the dragons, and the titties, and the motorboating.
我也醉了
Oy vey.
史黛芬小姐
Oh, Miss Stephanie.
她想到可以让弗莱明·梅修公司
She had the idea to link the Fleming-Mayhew company
跟新的基金会合作
with the new foundation.
赞助第三世界的污水处理工程 我就说吧
So now, they're sponsoring sewage projects all over the Third World. I told you.
冰雪聪明的女孩
Smart, smart, smart girl.
这帮人现在过得很开心
So, things are working out really well for the gang here.
[高速企业 冲上云霄]
公司红透半边天
The company is a smashing success.
我亲爱的莱德也终于实现了梦想
And my dear Laird has finally gotten what he's always wanted.
加入一个家庭
To be part of a family.
[圣诞快乐！]
先说到这里吧 我们下次见
All right, ciao for now, you friends.
莱德 被我看到就不算偷袭…
When I see Ryder, it's not a surprise attack
- 去你的 老古  - 靠
- Fuck you, Goose!  - Scheisse!
♪ I wanna rock and roll all night ♪
♪ And party every day ♪
♪ You keep on saying you'll be mine for a while ♪
♪ You're looking fancy and I like your style ♪
♪ You drive us wild, we'll drive you crazy ♪
♪ You show us everything you've got ♪
♪ Baby, baby, it's quite a lot ♪
♪ You drive us wild, we 'll drive you crazy ♪
♪ You keep on shouting, you keep on shouting ♪
♪ I wanna rock and roll all night ♪
♪ And party every day ♪